<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>nasa.gov on StarLord | Συλλέκτης Διαστημικών Ειδήσεων</title>
    <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/tags/nasa.gov/</link>
    <description>Recent content in nasa.gov on StarLord | Συλλέκτης Διαστημικών Ειδήσεων</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Thanks for visiting and clear skies!</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 Jun 2021 06:09:08 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/tags/nasa.gov/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>NGC 6888: The Crescent Nebula</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/ngc6888thecrescentnebula/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jun 2021 06:09:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/ngc6888thecrescentnebula/</guid>
      <description>NGC 6888, also known as the Crescent Nebula, is aabout 25 light-years acrossblown by windsfrom its central, bright, massive star.A triumvirate of astroimagers( Joe,Glenn,Russell)created this sharp portraitof the cosmic bubble.Their telescopic collaborationcollected over 30 hours of narrow band image data isolating light from hydrogenand oxygen atoms.The oxygen atoms produce the blue-green hue that seems to enshroudthe detailed folds and filaments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scorpius Enhanced</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/scorpiusenhanced/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jun 2021 06:10:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/scorpiusenhanced/</guid>
      <description>If Scorpius looked this good to the unaided eye, humans might remember it better. Scorpius more typically appears as a few bright stars in a well-known but rarely pointed out zodiacal constellation.To get a spectacular image like this, though, one needs a good camera, a dark sky, and some sophisticated image processing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zhurong: New Rover on Mars</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/zhurongnewroveronmars/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2021 06:07:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/zhurongnewroveronmars/</guid>
      <description>There&amp;rsquo;s a new rover on Mars.In mid-May, China&amp;rsquo;s Tianwen-1 mission delivered the Zhurong rover onto the red planet. As Mars means Planet of Fire in Chinese, the Zhurong rover&amp;rsquo;s name means, roughly, God of Fire in Chinese mythology. Zhurong landed in northern Utopia Planitia, the largest known impact basin in the Solar System, and an area reported to have much underground ice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ganymede from Juno</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/ganymedefromjuno/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jun 2021 06:07:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/ganymedefromjuno/</guid>
      <description>What does the largest moon in the Solar System look like? Jupiter&amp;rsquo;s moon Ganymede, larger than even Mercury and Pluto, has an icy surface speckled with bright young craters overlying a mixture of older, darker, more cratered terrain laced with grooves and ridges. The cause of the grooved terrain remains a topic of research, with a leading hypothesis relating it to shifting ice plates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Supercell Thunderstorm Over Texas</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/asupercellthunderstormovertexas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Jun 2021 06:06:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/asupercellthunderstormovertexas/</guid>
      <description>Is that a cloud or an alien spaceship? It&amp;rsquo;s an unusual and sometimes dangerous type of thunderstorm cloud called a supercell.Supercells may spawn damaging tornados, hail, downbursts of air, or drenching rain. Or they may just look impressive.A supercell harbors a mesocyclone &amp;ndash; a rising column of air surrounded by drafts of falling air.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eclipse on the Water</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/eclipseonthewater/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Jun 2021 06:07:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/eclipseonthewater/</guid>
      <description>Eclipses tend to come in pairs.Twice a year, during an eclipse season that lastsabout 34 days,Sun, Moon, and Earth can nearly align.Then the full and newphases of the Moonseparated by just over 14 days create a lunar and a solar eclipse.Often partial eclipses are part of any eclipse season.But sometimes the alignment at both new moon and full moonphases during a single eclipse season is close enoughto produce a pair of both total (or a total and an annular)lunar and solar eclipses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eclipse Flyby</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/eclipseflyby/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jun 2021 06:07:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/eclipseflyby/</guid>
      <description>On June 10 a New Moonpassed in front of the Sun.In silhouette only two days afterreaching apogee,the most distant point in its elliptical orbit,the Moon&amp;rsquo;s small apparent size helped create an annular solar eclipse.The brief but spectacular annular phase of the eclipseshows a bright solar disk as a ring of firewhen viewed along its narrow, northerly shadow track across planetEarth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Circular Sun Halo</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/circularsunhalo/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jun 2021 06:13:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/circularsunhalo/</guid>
      <description>Want to see a ring around the Sun?It&amp;rsquo;s easy to doin daytime skies around the world.Created by randomly oriented ice crystals in thin high cirrus clouds,circular 22 degree halos are visible much more often than rainbows.This one wascaptured by smart phonephotographyon May 29 near Rome, Italy.Carefullyblocking the Sun,for example with a finger tip,is usually all that it takes to revealthe common bright halo ring.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Total Lunar Eclipse Corona</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/atotallunareclipsecorona/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jun 2021 06:21:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/atotallunareclipsecorona/</guid>
      <description>This moon appears multiply strange. This moon was a full moon, specifically called a Flower Moon at this time of the year. But that didn&amp;rsquo;t make it strange &amp;ndash; full moons occur once a month (moon-th). This moon was a supermoon, meaning that it reached its full phase near its closest approach to the Earth in its slightly elliptical orbit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Face in the Clouds of Jupiter from Juno</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/afaceinthecloudsofjupiterfromjuno/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jun 2021 06:22:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/afaceinthecloudsofjupiterfromjuno/</guid>
      <description>What do you see in the clouds of Jupiter?On the largest scale, circling the planet, Jupiter has alternating light zones and reddish-brown belts.Rising zone gas, mostly hydrogen and helium, usually swirls around regions of high pressure.Conversely, falling belt gas usually whirls around regions of low pressure, like cyclones and hurricanes on Earth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Bright Nova in Cassiopeia</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/abrightnovaincassiopeia/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jun 2021 04:20:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/abrightnovaincassiopeia/</guid>
      <description>What’s that new spot of light in Cassiopeia?A nova. Although novas occur frequently throughout the universe, this nova, known as Nova Cas 2021 or V1405 Cas, became so unusually bright in the skies of Earth last month that it was visible to the unaided eye. Nova Cas 2021 first brightened in mid-March but then, unexpectedly,became even brighter in mid-May and remained quite bright for about a week.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Distorted Sunrise Eclipse</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/adistortedsunriseeclipse/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jun 2021 04:07:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/adistortedsunriseeclipse/</guid>
      <description>Yes, but have you ever seen a sunrise like this? Here, after initial cloudiness, the Sun appeared to rise in two pieces and during partial eclipse, causing the photographer to describe it as the most stunning sunrise of his life. The dark circle near the top of the atmospherically-reddened Sun is the Moon &amp;ndash; but so is the dark peak just below it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Shining Clouds of Mars</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/theshiningcloudsofmars/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jun 2021 04:09:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/theshiningcloudsofmars/</guid>
      <description>The weathered and layered face ofMount Mercou looms in the foregroundof this mosaic from the Curiosity Mars rover&amp;rsquo;s Mast Camera.Made up of 21 individual images the scene was recordedjust after sunset on March 19, the 3,063rd martian day of Curiosity&amp;rsquo;son going exploration of the Red Planet.In themartian twilight high altitude cloudsstill shine above, reflecting the light from the Sun below the local horizonlike thenoctilucent clouds of planet Earth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blood Monster Moon</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/bloodmonstermoon/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jun 2021 04:31:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/bloodmonstermoon/</guid>
      <description>On May 26, theFull Flower Moonwas caught in this single exposure as itemerged from Earth&amp;rsquo;s shadowand morning twilight began to wash overthe western sky.Posing close to the horizon near the end of totality,an eclipsed lunar disk is framed againstbare oak trees at Pinnacles National Parkin central California.The Earth&amp;rsquo;s shadow isn&amp;rsquo;t completely dark though.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Millions of Stars in Omega Centauri</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/millionsofstarsinomegacentauri/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jun 2021 05:07:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/millionsofstarsinomegacentauri/</guid>
      <description>Globular star clusterOmega Centauri,also known as NGC 5139, is some 15,000 light-years away.The cluster is packed with about 10 millionstars much older than the Sun within a volume about 150 light-years indiameter.It&amp;rsquo;s the largest and brightest of 200 or so knownglobularclusters that roam the halo of our Milky Way galaxy.Though most star clusters consist of stars with the same age andcomposition, the enigmatic Omega Cen exhibits the presence ofdifferentstellar populations with a spread of ages and chemical abundances.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Galactic Center in Stars, Gas, and Magnetism</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/thegalacticcenterinstarsgasandmagnetism/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2021 05:34:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/thegalacticcenterinstarsgasandmagnetism/</guid>
      <description>What&amp;rsquo;s going on near the center of our galaxy?To help find out, a newly detailed panorama has been composed that explores regions just above and below the galactic plane in radio and X-ray light. X-ray light taken by the orbiting Chandra Observatory is shown in orange (hot), green (hotter), and purple (hottest) and superposed with a highly detailed image in radio waves, shown in gray, acquired by the MeerKAT array.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Starlink over Orion</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/starlinkoverorion/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 05:37:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/starlinkoverorion/</guid>
      <description>What are those streaks across Orion?Most are reflections of sunlight from numerous Earth-orbiting Starlink satellites.Appearing by eye as a series of successive points floating across a twilight sky, the increasing number of SpaceX Starlink communication satellites are causing concern among many astronomers.On the positive side, Starlink and similar constellations make the post-sunset sky more dynamic, satellite-based global communications faster, and help provide digital services to currently underserved rural areas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mimas: Small Moon with a Big Crater</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/mimassmallmoonwithabigcrater/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 May 2021 15:53:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/mimassmallmoonwithabigcrater/</guid>
      <description>Whatever hit Mimas nearly destroyed it. What remains is one of thelargest impact craters on one ofSaturn&amp;rsquo;s smallest round moons. Analysis indicates that a slightly larger impact would have destroyed Mimas entirely. The huge crater, namedHerschel after the 1789 discoverer of Mimas,Sir William Herschel, spans about 130 kilometers and isfeatured here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aurora over Clouds</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/auroraoverclouds/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 May 2021 05:00:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/auroraoverclouds/</guid>
      <description>Auroras usually occur high above the clouds. The auroral glow is created when fast-moving particles ejected from the Sun impact the Earth&amp;rsquo;s magnetosphere, from which charged particles spiral along the Earth&amp;rsquo;s magnetic field to strike atoms and molecules high in the Earth&amp;rsquo;s atmosphere. An oxygen atom, for example, will glow in the green light commonly emitted by an aurora after being energized by such a collision.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lunar Dust and Duct Tape</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/lunardustandducttape/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 May 2021 05:02:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/lunardustandducttape/</guid>
      <description>Why is the Moon so dusty?On Earth, rocks are weathered by wind and water, creating soil and sand.On the Moon, the history of constant micrometeorite bombardmenthas blasted away at the rocky surface creating a layer of powderylunar soil or regolith. For the Apollo astronauts and their equipment,the pervasive, fine,gritty dust was definitely a problem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Total Lunar Eclipse from Sydney</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/totallunareclipsefromsydney/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 04:31:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/totallunareclipsefromsydney/</guid>
      <description>The reddened shadow of planet Earthplays across the lunardisk in this telescopic image taken on May 26 nearSydney, New South Wales, Australia.On that crisp, clear autumn night a Perigee Full Moonslid through the northern edge of the shadow&amp;rsquo;sdark central umbra.Shortfor a lunar eclipse,its total phaselasted only about 14 minutes.The Earth&amp;rsquo;s shadow was not completely dark though.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mid Eclipse and Milky Way</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/mideclipseandmilkyway/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 May 2021 06:34:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/mideclipseandmilkyway/</guid>
      <description>May&amp;rsquo;s perigee Full Moonslid through Earth&amp;rsquo;s shadow yesterdayentertaining night skygazers in regionsaround the Pacific.Seen from western North America, itsinks toward the rugged Sierra Nevada mountain range in thistime-lapse series of the total lunar eclipse.Low on the western horizon the Moon was captured atmid-eclipse with two separate exposures.Combined they reveal theeclipsed Moon&amp;rsquo;s reddened coloragainst the dark night skyand the diffuse starlight band of the Milky Way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Outburst Clouds of Star AG Car</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/theoutburstcloudsofstaragcar/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 May 2021 06:28:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/theoutburstcloudsofstaragcar/</guid>
      <description>What created these unusual clouds? At the center of this 2021 Hubble image sits AG Carinae, a supergiant star located about 20,000 light-years away in the southern constellation Carina. The star&amp;rsquo;s emitted power is over a million times that of the Sun, making AG Carinae one of the most luminous stars in our Milky Way galaxy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Moon During a Total Lunar Eclipse</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/themoonduringatotallunareclipse/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 06:21:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/themoonduringatotallunareclipse/</guid>
      <description>How does the Moon&amp;rsquo;s appearance change during a total lunar eclipse?The featured time-lapse video was digitally processed to keep the Moon bright and centered during the 5-hour eclipse of 2018 January 31. At first the full moon is visible because only a full moon can undergo a lunar eclipse. Stars move by in the background because the Moon orbits the Earth during the eclipse.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lightning Eclipse from the Planet of the Goats</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/lightningeclipsefromtheplanetofthegoats/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 06:12:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/lightningeclipsefromtheplanetofthegoats/</guid>
      <description>Thunderstorms almost spoiled this view of the spectacular 2011 June 15 total lunar eclipse.Instead, storm clouds parted for 10 minutes during thetotal eclipse phaseand lightning boltscontributed to the dramatic sky.Captured with a 30-second exposure the scene also inspired one of the more memorable titles (thanks to the astrophotographer)in APOD&amp;rsquo;s now 25-year history.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Galaxy Tree</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/thegalaxytree/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 May 2021 06:10:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/thegalaxytree/</guid>
      <description>First came the trees.In the town of Salamanca, Spain, the photographer noticed how distinctive a grove of oak trees looked after being pruned. Next came the galaxy.The photographer stayed up until 2 am, waiting until the Milky Way Galaxy rose above the level of a majestic looking oak. From this carefully chosen perspective, dust lanes in the galaxy appear to be natural continuations to branches of the tree.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Markarian s Chain</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/markarianschain/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 May 2021 06:09:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/markarianschain/</guid>
      <description>Near the heart of theVirgo Galaxy Clusterthe string of galaxies known as Markarian&amp;rsquo;sChain stretches across this deeptelescopic field of view.Anchored in the frame at bottom center by prominent lenticular galaxies,M84 (bottom)and M86,you can follow the chain up and to the right.Near center you&amp;rsquo;ll spot the pair of interacting galaxiesNGC 4438 and NGC 4435, known to some asMarkarian&amp;rsquo;s Eyes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Utopia on Mars</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/utopiaonmars/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 May 2021 06:09:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/utopiaonmars/</guid>
      <description>Expansive Utopia Planitiaon Mars is strewn with rocks and boulders in this 1976 image.Constructed fromtheViking 2 lander&amp;rsquo;scolor and black and white image data,the scene approximates the appearance of the high northern martianplain to the human eye.For scale, the prominent rounded rock near center is about 20centimeters (just under 8 inches) across.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>M13: The Great Globular Cluster in Hercules</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/m13thegreatglobularclusterinhercules/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 May 2021 06:10:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/m13thegreatglobularclusterinhercules/</guid>
      <description>In1716, English astronomerEdmond Halley noted,&amp;ldquo;This is but a little Patch, but it shews itself to the naked Eye, whenthe Sky is serene and the Moon absent.&amp;ldquo;Of course, M13is now less modestly recognized as the Great Globular Cluster inHercules, one of the brightestglobularstar clusters in the northern sky.Sharp telescopic views like this one reveal the spectacular cluster&amp;rsquo;shundreds of thousands of stars.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Jellyfish and Mars</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/thejellyfishandmars/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 May 2021 06:09:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/thejellyfishandmars/</guid>
      <description>Normally faint and elusive, the Jellyfish Nebula is caught inthis alluring scene.In the telescopic field of view two bright yellowish stars,Mu andEtaGeminorum, stand just below and above the Jellyfish Nebula at the left.Cool red giants, they lie at the foot of thecelestialtwin.The Jellyfish Nebula itself floats below and left of center, a bright arcingridge of emission with dangling tentacles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jets from the Necklace Nebula</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/jetsfromthenecklacenebula/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 May 2021 06:08:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/jetsfromthenecklacenebula/</guid>
      <description>What celestial body wears the Necklace Nebula?First, analyses indicate that the Necklace is a planetary nebula, a gas cloud emitted by a star toward the end of its life.Also, what appears to be diamonds in the Necklace are actually bright knots of glowing gas. In the center of the Necklace Nebula are likelytwo stars orbiting so close together that they share a common atmosphere and appear as one in the featured image by the Hubble Space Telescope.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NGC 4565: Galaxy on Edge</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/ngc4565galaxyonedge/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 May 2021 06:09:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/ngc4565galaxyonedge/</guid>
      <description>Is our Milky Way Galaxy this thin? Magnificent spiral galaxyNGC 4565is viewed edge-on from planet Earth.Also known as the Needle Galaxy for its narrow profile, bright NGC 4565 is a stop on many telescopic tours of the northern sky,in the faint but well-groomedconstellation ComaBerenices.This sharp, colorful image reveals the spiral galaxy&amp;rsquo;sboxy, bulgingcentral core cut byobscuring dust lanes that laceNGC 4565&amp;rsquo;s thin galactic plane.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NGC 602 and Beyond</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/ngc602andbeyond/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 May 2021 06:08:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/ngc602andbeyond/</guid>
      <description>The clouds may look like an oyster, and the stars like pearls, but look beyond.Near the outskirts of theSmall Magellanic Cloud,a satellite galaxy some 200 thousand light-years distant,lies 5 million year young star cluster NGC 602.Surrounded by natal gas and dust,NGC 602 is featured in thisstunning Hubble image of the region.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Southern Cliff in the Lagoon</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/thesoutherncliffinthelagoon/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 May 2021 06:10:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/thesoutherncliffinthelagoon/</guid>
      <description>Undulating bright ridges and dusty clouds crossthis close-up of thenearby star forming region M8, also known as theLagoon Nebula.A sharp, false-color composite of narrow band visible and broad bandnear-infrared data from the 8-meterGemini South Telescope,the entire view spans about 20 light-years through a regionof the nebula sometimes called the Southern Cliff.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>M104: The Sombrero Galaxy</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/m104thesombrerogalaxy/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 May 2021 06:08:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/m104thesombrerogalaxy/</guid>
      <description>A gorgeous spiral galaxy,M104 is famousfor its nearly edge-onprofile featuring a broad ring of obscuring dust lanes.Seen in silhouette against an extensive central bulge of stars,the swath of cosmic dust lends abroad brimmed hat-like appearance to the galaxy suggestinga more popular moniker, the Sombrero Galaxy.This sharp optical view of the well-known galaxy madefrom ground-based image data was processed to preservedetails often lost in overwhelming glare of M104&amp;rsquo;sbright central bulge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Comet, the Whale, and the Hockey Stick</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/thecometthewhaleandthehockeystick/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 06:08:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/thecometthewhaleandthehockeystick/</guid>
      <description>Closest to the Sun on March 1, andclosest to planet Earth on April 23, thisComet ATLAS (C/2020 R4)shows a faint greenish coma and short tailin this pretty, telescopic field of view.Captured at its position on May 5,the comet was within the boundaries of northern constellation Canes Venatici(the Hunting Dogs),and near the line-of-sight to intriguing background galaxies popularlyknown as theWhale and the Hockey Stick.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Meteor and the Gegenschein</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/ameteorandthegegenschein/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 06:08:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/ameteorandthegegenschein/</guid>
      <description>Is the night sky darkest in the direction opposite the Sun?No. In fact, a rarely discernable faint glow known as the gegenschein (German for &amp;ldquo;counter glow&amp;rdquo;) can be seen 180 degrees around from the Sun in an extremely dark sky.The gegenschein is sunlight back-scattered off small interplanetarydust particles. These dust particles are millimeter sized splinters from asteroids and orbit in the ecliptic plane of the planets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lightning and Orion Beyond Uluru</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/lightningandorionbeyonduluru/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 May 2021 06:05:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/lightningandorionbeyonduluru/</guid>
      <description>What&amp;rsquo;s happening behind Uluru? A United Nations World Heritage Site,Uluru is an extraordinary 350-meter high mountain in central Australia that rises sharply from nearly flat surroundings.Composed of sandstone, Uluru has slowly formed over the past 300 million years as softer rock eroded away. In the background of the featured image taken in mid-May, a raging thunderstorm is visible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Star Clusters M35 and NGC 2158</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/starclustersm35andngc2158/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 May 2021 06:06:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/starclustersm35andngc2158/</guid>
      <description>Clusters of stars can be near or far, young or old, diffuse or compact. The featured image shows two quite contrasting open star clusters in the same field.M35, on the lower left, is relatively nearby at 2800light years distant, relatively young at 150 million years old, and relatively diffuse, with about 2500 stars spread out over a volume 30 light years across.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Horsehead and Orion Nebulas</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/horseheadandorionnebulas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 May 2021 06:06:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/horseheadandorionnebulas/</guid>
      <description>The dark Horsehead Nebula and the glowingOrion Nebula are contrasting cosmic vistas.Adrift 1,500 light-years away in one ofthe night sky&amp;rsquo;smost recognizableconstellations,they appear in opposite corners of the abovestunning mosaic.The familiar Horseheadnebula appears as a dark cloud, a small silhouettenotched against the long red glow at the lower left.Alnitak is the easternmost star inOrion&amp;rsquo;s belt and is seen as the brightest star to the left of theHorsehead.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deepscape at Yacoraite</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/deepscapeatyacoraite/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 May 2021 06:05:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/deepscapeatyacoraite/</guid>
      <description>In this evocative night scene a dusty central Milky Wayrises over theancient Andeanarchaeological site of Yacoraite innorthwestern Argentina.The denizens of planet Earthreaching skywardare the large Argentine saguaro cactus currentlynative to the arid region.The unusual yellow-hued reflection nebula above is created bydust scattering starlightaround red giant star Antares.Alpha star of the constellation Scorpius,Antares is over 500 light-years distant.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mercury Redstone 3 Launch</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/mercuryredstone3launch/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 May 2021 06:05:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/mercuryredstone3launch/</guid>
      <description>Sixty years ago, near thedawn of the space age,NASA controllers &amp;ldquo;lit the candle&amp;rdquo; and sentMercury astronaut Alan Shepardarcing into space atop a Redstone rocket.His cramped space capsule was dubbed Freedom 7.Broadcast live to a global television audience, the historicMercury-Redstone 3(MR-3) spacecraft was launched fromCape Canaveral Florida at 9:34 a.m. Eastern Time on May 5, 1961.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Windblown NGC 3199</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/windblownngc3199/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 May 2021 06:07:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/windblownngc3199/</guid>
      <description>NGC 3199 lies about 12,000 light-years away,a glowing cosmic cloud in the nautical southern constellationof Carina.The nebula is about 75 light-years across in thisnarrowband, false-color view. Though the deep image reveals a more or less completebubble shape, it does look very lopsided with a much brighter edgealong the top.Near the center is aWolf-Rayet star,a massive, hot, short-lived star that generates an intense stellar wind.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>STEVE over Copper Harbor</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/steveovercopperharbor/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 May 2021 06:06:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/steveovercopperharbor/</guid>
      <description>What creates STEVEs?Strong Thermal Emission Velocity Enhancements (STEVEs) have likely been seen since antiquity, but only in the past five years has it been realized that their colors and shapes make them different from auroras.Seen as single bright streaks of pink and purple, the origin of STEVEs remain an active topic of research.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Space Station, Solar Prominences, Sun</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/spacestationsolarprominencessun/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 May 2021 06:05:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/spacestationsolarprominencessun/</guid>
      <description>That&amp;rsquo;s no sunspot.It&amp;rsquo;s the International Space Station (ISS) caught passing in front of the Sun.Sunspots, individually, have a dark central umbra, a lighter surrounding penumbra, and no Dragon capsules attached. By contrast, the ISS is a complex and multi-spired mechanism, one of the largest and most complicated spacecraft ever created by humanity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apollo 11: Earth, Moon, Spaceship</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/apollo11earthmoonspaceship/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 May 2021 06:02:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/apollo11earthmoonspaceship/</guid>
      <description>After the most famous voyage of modern times, it was time to go home.After proving that humanity has the ability to go beyond the confines of planet Earth, the first humans to walk on another world &amp;ndash; Neil Armstrong and Buzz Aldrin &amp;ndash; flew the ascent stage of their Lunar Module back to meet Michael Collins in the moon-orbiting Command and Service Module.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clouds of the Carina Nebula</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/cloudsofthecarinanebula/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 May 2021 06:03:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/cloudsofthecarinanebula/</guid>
      <description>What forms lurk in the mists of the Carina Nebula?The dark ominous figures are actually molecular clouds, knots of molecular gas and dust so thick they have become opaque. In comparison, however, these clouds are typically much less dense than Earth&amp;rsquo;s atmosphere. Featured here is a detailed image of the core of the Carina Nebula, a part where both dark and colorful clouds of gas and dust are particularly prominent.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Perseverance from Ingenuity</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/perseverancefromingenuity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2021 09:03:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/perseverancefromingenuity/</guid>
      <description>Flying at an altitude of 5 meters(just over 16 feet), on April 25 the Ingenuity helicoptersnapped this sharp image.On its second flight above the surface of Mars,its color camera was looking back toward Ingenuity&amp;rsquo;s current base atWright Brothers Fieldand Octavia E. Butler Landing marked by the tracks of thePerseverance rover at the top of the frame.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pink and the Perigee Moon</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/pinkandtheperigeemoon/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Apr 2021 06:02:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/pinkandtheperigeemoon/</guid>
      <description>On April 25 a nearly full moon rose just before sunset.Welcomed in a clear blue sky and framed by cherry blossoms,its familiar face was captured in this snapshotfrom Leith, Edinburgh, Scotland.Known to some as a Pink Moon,April&amp;rsquo;sfull lunar phaseoccurred with the moon near perigee.That&amp;rsquo;s the closest point in itsnot-quite-circularorbit around planet Earth,making this Pink Moon one of the closest and brightest full moonsof the year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apollo 17: The Crescent Earth</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/apollo17thecrescentearth/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 06:05:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/apollo17thecrescentearth/</guid>
      <description>Our fair planetsports a curved, sunlit crescentagainst the black backdrop of space in this stunning photograph.From the unfamiliar perspective,the Earth is smalland, like atelescopic image of a distant planet,the entire horizon is completely within the field of view.Enjoyed bycrews on boardthe International Space Station,only much closer views of the planet are possible from low Earth orbit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>North Star: Polaris and Surrounding Dust</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/northstarpolarisandsurroundingdust/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Apr 2021 06:03:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/northstarpolarisandsurroundingdust/</guid>
      <description>Why is Polaris called the North Star?First, Polaris is the nearest bright star toward the north spin axis of the Earth. Therefore, as the Earth turns, stars appear to revolve around Polaris, but Polaris itself always stays in the same northerly direction &amp;ndash; making it the North Star. Since no bright star is near the south spin axis of the Earth, there is currently no South Star.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Animation: Black Hole Star Shredder</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/animationblackholestarshredder/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Apr 2021 06:03:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/animationblackholestarshredder/</guid>
      <description>What happens if a star gets too close to a black hole?The black hole can rip it apart &amp;ndash; but how?It&amp;rsquo;s not the high gravitational attraction itself that&amp;rsquo;s the problem &amp;ndash; it&amp;rsquo;s the difference in gravitational pull across the star that creates the destruction. In the featured animated video illustrating this disintegration, you first see a star approaching the black hole.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Sagittarius Triplet</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/asagittariustriplet/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Apr 2021 06:03:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/asagittariustriplet/</guid>
      <description>These three bright nebulae are often featured on telescopic tours of theconstellation Sagittarius and the crowded starfields ofthe central Milky Way.In fact, 18th century cosmic touristCharles Messiercataloged two of them; M8,the large nebula below and right of center,and colorful M20near the top of the frame.The third emission region includesNGC 6559, left of M8 andseparated from the larger nebula by a dark dust lane.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Planetary Nebula Mz3: The Ant Nebula</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/planetarynebulamz3theantnebula/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Apr 2021 06:03:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/planetarynebulamz3theantnebula/</guid>
      <description>Why isn&amp;rsquo;t this ant a big sphere? Planetary nebula Mz3 is being cast off by a star similar to our Sun that is, surely, round. Why then would the gas that is streaming away create an ant-shaped nebula that is distinctly not round? Clues might includethe high 1000-kilometer per second speed of the expelled gas, the light-year long length of the structure, and the magnetism of the star featured here at the nebula&amp;rsquo;s center.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Streak and Plume from SpaceX Crew2 Launch</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/streakandplumefromspacexcrew2launch/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Apr 2021 06:02:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/streakandplumefromspacexcrew2launch/</guid>
      <description>What&amp;rsquo;s happening in the sky? The pre-dawn sky first seemed relatively serene yesterday morning over Indian Harbor Beach in Florida, USA.But then it lit up with a rocket launch. Just to the north, NASA&amp;rsquo;s SpaceX Crew-2 Mission blasted into space aboard a powerful Falcon 9 rocket.The featured time-lapse video &amp;ndash; compressing 12-minutes into 8-seconds &amp;ndash; shows the bright launch plume starting on the far left.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flying Over the Earth at Night II</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/flyingovertheearthatnightii/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Apr 2021 06:03:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/flyingovertheearthatnightii/</guid>
      <description>Recorded during 2017, timelapse sequences from theInternational Space Station are compiled in thisserene video of planet Earth at Night.Fans of low Earth orbit can start by enjoying the view asgreen and red aurora borealisslather up the sky.The night scene tracks from northwest to southeast across North America,toward the Gulf of Mexico and the Florida coast.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Planet Earth at Twilight</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/planetearthattwilight/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Apr 2021 06:05:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/planetearthattwilight/</guid>
      <description>No sudden, sharp boundary marks the passage of day into night inthis gorgeous viewof ocean and clouds overour fair planet Earth.Instead, the shadow line or terminator is diffuse and showsthe gradual transition to darkness we experience as twilight.With the Sun illuminating the scene from the right,the cloud tops reflect gently reddenedsunlightfilteredthrough the dusty troposphere,the lowest layer of the planet&amp;rsquo;s nurturing atmosphere.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Centaurus As Warped Magnetic Fields</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/centaurusaswarpedmagneticfields/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Apr 2021 06:03:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/centaurusaswarpedmagneticfields/</guid>
      <description>When galaxies collide &amp;ndash; what happens to their magnetic fields?To help find out, NASA pointed SOFIA, its flying 747, at galactic neighbor Centaurus A to observe the emission of polarized dust &amp;ndash; which traces magnetic fields. Cen A&amp;rsquo;s unusual shape results from the clash of two galaxies with jets powered by gas accreting onto a central supermassive black hole.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ingenuity: First Flight over Mars</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/ingenuityfirstflightovermars/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Apr 2021 06:03:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/ingenuityfirstflightovermars/</guid>
      <description>What&amp;rsquo;s the best way to explore Mars?Perhaps there is no single best way, but a newly demonstrated method shows tremendous promise: flight.Powered flight has the promise to search vast regions and scout out particularly interesting areas for more detailed investigation. Yesterday, for the first time, powered flight was demonstrated on Mars by a small helicopter named Ingenuity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Galactic Center in Infrared</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/thegalacticcenterininfrared/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Apr 2021 06:03:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/thegalacticcenterininfrared/</guid>
      <description>What does the center of our galaxy look like? In visible light, the Milky Way&amp;rsquo;s center is hidden by clouds ofobscuring dust and gas.But in this stunning vista, the Spitzer Space Telescope&amp;rsquo;sinfrared cameras, penetrate much of thedust revealing the stars of the crowdedgalactic centerregion.A mosaic of many smaller snapshots, the detailed,false-color image showsolder, cool stars in bluish hues.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rainbow Airglow over the Azores</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/rainbowairglowovertheazores/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Apr 2021 21:39:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/rainbowairglowovertheazores/</guid>
      <description>Why would the sky glow like a giant repeating rainbow? Airglow. Now air glows all of the time, but it is usually hard to see.A disturbance however &amp;ndash; like an approaching storm &amp;ndash; may cause noticeable rippling in the Earth&amp;rsquo;s atmosphere.These gravity waves are oscillations in air analogous to those created when a rock is thrown in calm water.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Confirmed Muon Wobble Remains Unexplained</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/confirmedmuonwobbleremainsunexplained/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Apr 2021 06:02:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/confirmedmuonwobbleremainsunexplained/</guid>
      <description>How fast do elementary particles wobble? A surprising answer to this seemingly inconsequential question came out of Brookhaven National Laboratory in New York, USA in 2001, and indicated that the Standard Model of Particle Physics, adopted widely in physics,is incomplete.Specifically, the muon, a particle with similarities to a heavy electron, has had its relatively large wobble under scrutiny in a series of experiments known as g-2 (gee-minus-two).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alnitak and the Flame Nebula</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/alnitakandtheflamenebula/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2021 06:02:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/alnitakandtheflamenebula/</guid>
      <description>What lights up the Flame Nebula? Fifteen hundredlight years away towards the constellation of Orion lies a nebula which, from its glow and darkdust lanes,appears, on the left, like a billowing fire. But fire,the rapid acquisition ofoxygen,is not what makes thisFlame glow. Rather the bright star Alnitak, the easternmost star in theBelt of Orionvisible on the far left, shines energetic light into theFlame that knocks electrons away from the great clouds of hydrogengas that reside there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When Black Holes Collide</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/whenblackholescollide/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Apr 2021 06:02:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/whenblackholescollide/</guid>
      <description>What happens when two black holes collide?This extreme scenario occurs in the centers of many merging galaxies and multiple star systems.The featured video shows a computer animation of the final stages of such a merger, while highlighting the gravitational lensing effects that would appear on a background starfield.The black regions indicate the event horizons of the dynamic duo, while a surrounding ring of shifting background stars indicates the position of their combined Einstein ring.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zodiacal Night</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/zodiacalnight/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Apr 2021 06:02:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/zodiacalnight/</guid>
      <description>An intense band of zodiacal lightis captured in this serene mountain and night skyscape from April 7.The panoramic view was recorded after three hours of hikingfrom a vantage looking west after sunset across the Pyreneesin southern France.At 2838 meters altitude, Mont Valier is the tallest peak near center.In the sky above, thefamiliar stars ofOrion and the northern winterMilky Way are approaching the rugged western horizon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Messier 106</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/messier106/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Apr 2021 06:02:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/messier106/</guid>
      <description>Close to the Great Bear(Ursa Major) and surrounded by the stars of theHunting Dogs(Canes Venatici), this celestial wonder wasdiscoveredin 1781 by themetricFrench astronomerPierre Mechain.Later, it was added to the catalog of his friend and colleagueCharles Messier asM106.Modern deep telescopic views reveal it to be anisland universe -a spiral galaxy around 30 thousand light-years across locatedonly about 21 million light-years beyond the stars of the Milky Way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3D Ingenuity</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/3dingenuity/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Apr 2021 12:19:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/3dingenuity/</guid>
      <description>The multicolor, stereo imagingMastcam-Zon the Perseverance roverzoomed in to capturedthis 3D close-up (get out your red/blue glasses) of theMars Ingenuity helicopteron mission sol 45, April 5.That&amp;rsquo;s only a few sols before thetechnology demonstrating Ingenuitywill attempt to fly in the thin martian atmosphere, makingthe first powered flight on another planet.The historic test flight is plannedfor no earlier than Sunday, April 11.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Threads of NGC 1947</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/threadsofngc1947/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Apr 2021 06:03:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/threadsofngc1947/</guid>
      <description>Found in far southern skies, deep within the boundaries of theconstellation Dorado,NGC 1947 is some 40 million light-years away.In silhouette against starlight, obscuring lanes of cosmic dustthread across the peculiar galaxy&amp;rsquo;s bright central regions.Unlike the rotation of stars, gas, and dust tracing the arms ofspiral galaxies, the motions of dust and gas don&amp;rsquo;t follow the motions of starsin NGC 1947 though.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mars and the Pleiades Beyond Vinegar Hill</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/marsandthepleiadesbeyondvinegarhill/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Apr 2021 06:03:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/marsandthepleiadesbeyondvinegarhill/</guid>
      <description>Is this just a lonely tree on an empty hill?To start, perhaps, but look beyond. There, a busy universe may wait to be discovered.First, physically, to the left of the tree, is the planet Mars.The red planet, which is the new home to NASA&amp;rsquo;s Perseverance rover, remains visible this month at sunset above the western horizon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Veil Nebula: Wisps of an Exploded Star</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/veilnebulawispsofanexplodedstar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Apr 2021 04:09:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/veilnebulawispsofanexplodedstar/</guid>
      <description>Wisps like this are all that remain visible of a Milky Way star. About 7,000 years ago that star exploded in asupernova leaving theVeil Nebula.At the time, the expanding cloudwas likely as bright as a crescent Moon, remainingvisible for weeks to people living at the dawn ofrecorded history. Today, the resulting supernova remnant, also known as the Cygnus Loop, has faded and isnow visible only through a small telescopedirectedtoward theconstellation of the Swan(Cygnus).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In, Through, and Beyond Saturn&#39;s Rings</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/inthroughandbeyondsaturnsrings/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Apr 2021 04:09:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/inthroughandbeyondsaturnsrings/</guid>
      <description>Four moons are visible on the featured image &amp;ndash; can you find them all?First &amp;ndash; and farthest in the background &amp;ndash; is Titan, the largest moon of Saturn and one of the larger moons in the Solar System. The dark feature across the top of this perpetually cloudy world is the north polar hood.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ingenuity on Sol 39</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/ingenuityonsol39/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Apr 2021 04:08:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/ingenuityonsol39/</guid>
      <description>The Mars Ingenuity Helicopter,all four landing legs down,was captured here on sol 39 (March 30) slung beneath the belly ofthe Perseverance rover.The near ground level view is a mosaic of imagesfrom the WATSON camera on the rover&amp;rsquo;s SHERLOC robotic arm.Near the center of the frame the experimental helicopteris suspended just a few centimeters above the martian surface.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NGC 3521: Galaxy in a Bubble</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/ngc3521galaxyinabubble/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Apr 2021 04:10:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/ngc3521galaxyinabubble/</guid>
      <description>Gorgeous spiral galaxy NGC 3521 is a mere 35 million light-years away,toward theconstellation Leo.Relatively bright in planet Earth&amp;rsquo;s sky, NGC 3521 iseasily visible in small telescopes but often overlooked byamateur imagers in favor of other Leo spiral galaxies,like M66 and M65.It&amp;rsquo;s hard to overlook inthis colorful cosmic portrait, though.Spanning some 50,000 light-years the galaxy sportscharacteristicpatchy, irregular spiral arms laced with dust, pink star formingregions, and clusters of young, blue stars.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rocket Launch as Seen from the Space Station</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/rocketlaunchasseenfromthespacestation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2021 04:07:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/rocketlaunchasseenfromthespacestation/</guid>
      <description>Have you ever seen a rocket launch &amp;ndash; from space? A close inspection of the featured time-lapse video will reveal a rocket rising to Earth orbit as seen from the International Space Station (ISS). The Russian Soyuz-FG rocket was launched in November 2018 from the Baikonur Cosmodrome in Kazakhstan, carrying a Progress MS-10 (also 71P) module to bring needed supplies to the ISS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>M87s Central Black Hole in Polarized Light</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/m87scentralblackholeinpolarizedlight/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Mar 2021 04:08:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/m87scentralblackholeinpolarizedlight/</guid>
      <description>To play on Carl Sagan’s famous words &amp;ldquo;If you wish to make black hole jets, you must first create magnetic fields.&amp;ldquo;The featured image represents the detected intrinsic spin direction (polarization) of radio waves. The polarizationi is produced by the powerful magnetic field surrounding the supermassive black hole at the center of elliptical galaxy M87.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Red Sprite Lightning over the Andes</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/redspritelightningovertheandes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 04:08:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/redspritelightningovertheandes/</guid>
      <description>What are those red filaments in the sky?They are a rarely seen form of lightning confirmed only about 30 years ago: red sprites.Recent research has shown that following a powerful positivecloud-to-ground lightning strike,red sprites may start as 100-meter balls ofionizedair that shoot down from about80-km high at 10 percent the speed of light.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>M64: The Evil Eye Galaxy</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/m64theevileyegalaxy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Mar 2021 04:10:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/m64theevileyegalaxy/</guid>
      <description>Who knows what evil lurks in the eyes of galaxies?The Hubble knows &amp;ndash; or in the case of spiral galaxy M64 &amp;ndash; is helping to find out.Messier 64, also known as the Evil Eye or Sleeping Beauty Galaxy, may seem to have evil in its eye because all of its stars rotate in the same direction as the interstellar gas in the galaxy&amp;rsquo;s central region, but in the opposite direction in the outer regions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SuitSat 1: A Spacesuit Floats Free</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/suitsat1aspacesuitfloatsfree/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Mar 2021 04:10:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/suitsat1aspacesuitfloatsfree/</guid>
      <description>A spacesuit floated away from the International Space Station 15 years ago, but no investigation was conducted. Everyone knew that it was pushed by the space station crew. Dubbed Suitsat-1, the unneeded Russian Orlan spacesuit filled mostly with old clothes was fitted with a faint radio transmitter and released to orbit the Earth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the Antennae</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/exploringtheantennae/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Mar 2021 04:08:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/exploringtheantennae/</guid>
      <description>Some 60 million light-years away in the southerlyconstellationCorvus, two large galaxies are colliding.Stars in the two galaxies, cataloged asNGC 4038 and NGC 4039,very rarely collide in the course of theponderous cataclysm that lasts for hundreds of millions of years.But the galaxies&amp;rsquo; largeclouds of molecular gas and dustoften do, triggeringfurious episodes of star formationinear the center of thecosmic wreckage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Medusa Nebula</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/themedusanebula/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Mar 2021 04:13:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/themedusanebula/</guid>
      <description>Braided and serpentine filaments of glowing gassuggest this nebula&amp;rsquo;s popular name, The Medusa Nebula.Also known as Abell 21, this Medusa is an oldplanetary nebulasome 1,500 light-years away in the constellation Gemini.Like its mythologicalnamesake, the nebula is associated with a dramatic transformation.The planetarynebula phase represents a final stage intheevolution of low mass stars like the sunas they transform themselves fromred giantsto hot white dwarfstars and in the process shrug off their outer layers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Curiosity: Sol 3048</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/curiositysol3048/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Mar 2021 04:10:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/curiositysol3048/</guid>
      <description>BeforePerseverance there was Curiosity.In fact, the Curiosity rover accomplished the first sky crane maneuvertouchdown on Mars on April 5, 2012.March 2, 2021 marked Curiosity&amp;rsquo;s 3,048th martian day operatingon the surface of the Red Planet.This 360 degree panoramafromsol 3048 is a mosaic of 149 framesfrom Curiosity&amp;rsquo;s Mastcam above the rover&amp;rsquo;s deck.It includes 23 frames oficy, thin, high cloudsdrifting through the martian sky.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aurorae and Lightning on Jupiter</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/auroraeandlightningonjupiter/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2021 04:08:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/auroraeandlightningonjupiter/</guid>
      <description>Why does so much of Jupiter&amp;rsquo;s lightning occur near its poles?Similar to Earth, Jupiter experiences both aurorae and lightning.Different from Earth, though, Jupiter&amp;rsquo;s lightning usually occurs near itspoles &amp;ndash; while much of Earth&amp;rsquo;s lightning occurs near its equator.To help understand the difference, NASA&amp;rsquo;s Juno spacecraft, currently orbiting Jupiter, has observed numerous aurora and lightning events.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mars over Duddo Stone Circle</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/marsoverduddostonecircle/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 04:28:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/marsoverduddostonecircle/</guid>
      <description>Why are these large stones here?One the more famous stone circles is the Duddo Five Stones of Northumberland, England. Set in the open near the top of a modest incline, a short hike across empty fields will bring you to unusual human-sized stones that are unlike anything surrounding them.The grooved, pitted, and deeply weathered surfaces of the soft sandstones are consistent with being placed about 4000 years ago &amp;ndash; but placed for reasons now unknown.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Auriga to Orion</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/fromaurigatoorion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Mar 2021 04:32:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/fromaurigatoorion/</guid>
      <description>What&amp;rsquo;s up in the sky from Auriga to Orion?Many of the famous stars and nebulas in this region were captured on 34 separate images, taking over 430 hours of exposure, and digitally combined to reveal the featured image.Starting on the far upper left, toward the constellation of Auriga (the Chariot driver), is the picturesque Flaming Star Nebula (IC 405).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Antikythera Mechanism</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/theantikytheramechanism/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 05:27:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/theantikytheramechanism/</guid>
      <description>No one knew that 2,000 years ago, the technology existed to build such a device. The Antikythera mechanism, pictured, is now widely regarded as the first computer.Found at the bottom of the sea aboard a decaying Greek ship, its complexity prompted decades of study, and even today some of its functions likely remain unknown.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Leo Trio</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/theleotrio/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Mar 2021 14:33:38 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/theleotrio/</guid>
      <description>This popular group leaps into the early evening sky around the Marchequinox andthenorthern hemisphere spring.Famous as theLeo Triplet,the three magnificent galaxies found in the prominentconstellation Leogather here in one astronomical field of view.Crowd pleasers when imaged with even modesttelescopes, they can be introduced individually asNGC 3628 (right), M66 (upper left), and M65 (bottom).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Central Lagoon in Infrared</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/centrallagoonininfrared/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2021 13:45:37 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/centrallagoonininfrared/</guid>
      <description>Stars fill this infrared view, spanning 4 light-years across the centerof the Lagoon Nebula.Visible light imagesshow the glowing gas and obscuring dust clouds thatdominate the scene.But this infrared image,constructed fromHubble Space Telescope data,peers closer to the heart of the active star-forming region revealingnewborn stars scattered within,against a crowded field of background starstoward the center of our Milky Way galaxy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stardust in the Perseus Molecular Cloud</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/stardustintheperseusmolecularcloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Mar 2021 13:38:29 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/stardustintheperseusmolecularcloud/</guid>
      <description>Clouds of stardust drift through this deep skyscape,across thePerseus molecular cloudsome 850 light-years away.Dusty nebulae reflecting light from embedded young starsstand out in the nearly 2 degree wide telescopic field of view.With a characteristic bluish colorreflection nebula NGC 1333 is atcenter,vdB 13 at top right,with rare yellowish reflection nebulavdB 12 near the top of the frame.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Surface of Venus from Venera 13</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/thesurfaceofvenusfromvenera13/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Mar 2021 13:31:04 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/thesurfaceofvenusfromvenera13/</guid>
      <description>If you could stand on Venus &amp;ndash; what would you see? Pictured is the view from Venera 13, a robotic Soviet lander which parachuted and air-braked down through the thick Venusian atmosphere in March of 1982.The desolate landscape it saw included flat rocks, vast empty terrain, and a featureless sky above Phoebe Regio near Venus&amp;rsquo; equator.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IC 1318 The Butterfly Nebula in Gas and Dust</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/ic1318thebutterflynebulaingasanddust/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Mar 2021 13:24:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/ic1318thebutterflynebulaingasanddust/</guid>
      <description>In the constellation of the swan near the nebula of the pelican lies the gas cloud of the butterfly next to a star known as the hen. That star, given the proper name Sadr, is just to the right of the featured frame, but the central Butterfly Nebula, designated IC 1318, is shown in high resolution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Flag Shaped Aurora over Sweden</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/aflagshapedauroraoversweden/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Mar 2021 13:14:45 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/aflagshapedauroraoversweden/</guid>
      <description>It appeared, momentarily, like a 50-km tall banded flag. In mid-March of 2015, an energetic Coronal Mass Ejection directed toward a clear magnetic channel to Earth led to one of the more intense geomagnetic storms of recent years.A visual result was wide spread auroras being seen over many countries near Earth&amp;rsquo;s magnetic poles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SuperCam Target on Maaz</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/supercamtargetonmaaz/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Mar 2021 13:08:59 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/supercamtargetonmaaz/</guid>
      <description>What&amp;rsquo;s the sound ofone laser zapping?There&amp;rsquo;s no need to consult a Zen master to find out,just listen to the firstacoustic recording of laser shots on Mars.On Perseverance mission sol 12 (March 2) the SuperCam instrument atopthe rover&amp;rsquo;s mast zapped a rock dubbed Ma&amp;rsquo;az 30 times from a range ofabout 3.1 meters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Messier 81</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/messier81/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 12:58:37 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/messier81/</guid>
      <description>One of the brightest galaxies in planet Earth&amp;rsquo;s sky is similar in sizeto our Milky Way Galaxy: big,beautifulMessier 81.Also known as NGC 3031 or Bode&amp;rsquo;s galaxy for its 18th century discoverer,this grand spiralcan be found toward the northern constellation of Ursa Major, the Great Bear.The sharp,detailed telescopic view reveals M81&amp;rsquo;s bright yellow nucleus, bluespiral arms, pinkish starforming regions, and sweepingcosmic dust lanes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zodiacal Light and Mars</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/zodiacallightandmars/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 12:49:31 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/zodiacallightandmars/</guid>
      <description>Just after sunset on March 7, a faint band of light stillreaches above the western horizon in this serene,rural Illinois, night skyscape.Taken from an old farmstead, the luminous glow is zodiacal light,prominent in the west after sunset during planet Earth&amp;rsquo;snorthern hemisphere spring.On that clear evening the band of zodiacal light seemsto engulf bright yellowish Mars and the Pleiades star cluster.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NGC 1499 The California Nebula</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/ngc1499thecalifornianebula/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 12:39:17 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/ngc1499thecalifornianebula/</guid>
      <description>Could Queen Calafia&amp;rsquo;s mythical island exist in space?Perhaps not, but by chance the outline of this molecular space cloud echoes the outline of the state of California, USA.Our Sun has its home within the Milky Way&amp;rsquo;sOrionArm, only about 1,000 light-years from the California Nebula.Also known as NGC 1499, the classic emission nebula is around 100 light-years long.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Three Tails of Comet NEOWISE</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/threetailsofcometneowise/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 10:24:20 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/threetailsofcometneowise/</guid>
      <description>What created the unusual red tail in Comet NEOWISE?Sodium. A spectacular sight back in the summer of 2020, Comet NEOWISE, at times, displayed something more than just a surprisinglystriated white dust tail and a pleasingly patchy blue ion tail.Some color sensitive images showed an unusual red tail, and analysis showed much of this third tail&amp;rsquo;s color was emitted by sodium.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pillars of the Eagle Nebula in Infrared</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/pillarsoftheeaglenebulaininfrared/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Mar 2021 10:21:07 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/pillarsoftheeaglenebulaininfrared/</guid>
      <description>Newborn stars are forming in the Eagle Nebula. Gravitationally contracting in pillars of dense gas and dust, the intense radiation of these newly-formed bright stars is causing surrounding material to boil away.This image, taken with the Hubble Space Telescope in near infrared light, allows the viewer to see through much of the thick dust that makes the pillars opaque in visible light.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Perseverance Takes a Spin</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/perseverancetakesaspin/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Mar 2021 10:15:10 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/perseverancetakesaspin/</guid>
      <description>After arriving at Jezero Crater on Mars,Perseverance went for a spinon March 4.This sharp imagefrom the car-sized rover&amp;rsquo;s Navcam shows tracks leftby itswheels in the martian soil.In preparation for operations on the surface of the Red Planet, itsfirst drive lasted about 33 minutes.On a short and successful test drivePerseverance movedforward 4 meters,made a 150 degree turn,backed up for 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Little Like Mars</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/alittlelikemars/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Mar 2021 10:07:24 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/alittlelikemars/</guid>
      <description>The surfaceof this planet looks a littlelike Mars.It&amp;rsquo;s really planet Earththough.In a digitally stitched little planet projection, the360 degree mosaic was captured near San Pedro in the ChileanAtacama desert.Telescopes in domes on the horizon are takingadvantage of the region&amp;rsquo;s famously dark, clear nights.Taken in early December, a magnificentMilky Way arcs above the horizonfor almost 180 degrees around the little planet with Orionprominent in the southern sky.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mars in Taurus</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/marsintaurus/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Mar 2021 09:57:59 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/marsintaurus/</guid>
      <description>You can spot Marsin the evening sky tonight.Now home to thePerseverance rover,the Red Planetis presently wandering through the constellation Taurus, close on the sky tothe Seven Sisters or Pleiades star cluster.In factthis deep, widefield viewof the regioncaptures Mars near its closest conjunction to the Pleiades on March 3.Below center, Mars is the bright yellowish celestial beacon only about 3degrees from the pretty blue star cluster.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stars over an Erupting Volcano</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/starsoveraneruptingvolcano/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Mar 2021 09:52:16 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/starsoveraneruptingvolcano/</guid>
      <description>Mt. Etna has been erupting for hundreds of thousands of years. Located in Sicily, Italy, the volcano produces lava fountains over one kilometer high. Mt. Etna is not only one of the most active volcanoes on Earth, it is one of the largest, measuring over 50 kilometers at its base and rising nearly 3 kilometers high.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ingenuity A Mini Helicopter Now on Mars</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/ingenuityaminihelicopternowonmars/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Mar 2021 09:45:24 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/ingenuityaminihelicopternowonmars/</guid>
      <description>What if you could fly around Mars? NASA may have achieved that capability last month with the landing of Perseverance, a rover which included a small flight-worthy companion called Ingenuity, nicknamed Ginny.Even though Ginny is small &amp;ndash; a toaster-sized helicopter with four long legs and two even-longer (1.2-meter) rotors, she is the first of her kind &amp;ndash; there has never been anything like her before.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Pelican Nebula in Red and Blue</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/thepelicannebulainredandblue/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2021 21:41:23 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/thepelicannebulainredandblue/</guid>
      <description>The Pelican Nebula is changing. The entire nebula, officially designated IC 5070, is divided from the larger North America Nebula by a molecular cloud filled with dark dust. The Pelican, however, is particularly interesting because it is an unusually active mix of star formation and evolving gas clouds. The featured picture was processed to bring out two main colors, red and blue, with thered dominated by light emitted by interstellar hydrogen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Aurora Tree</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/theauroratree/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2021 01:00:07 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/theauroratree/</guid>
      <description>Yes, but can your tree do this? Pictured is a visual coincidence between the dark branches of a nearby tree and bright glow of a distant aurora.The beauty of the aurora &amp;ndash; combined with how it seemed to mimic a tree right nearby &amp;ndash; mesmerized the photographer to such a degree that he momentarily forgot to take pictures.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Perseverance Landing Site from Mars Reconnaissance Orbiter</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/perseverancelandingsitefrommarsreconnaissanceorbiter/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Feb 2021 16:11:47 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/perseverancelandingsitefrommarsreconnaissanceorbiter/</guid>
      <description>Seen from orbit a day after adramatic arrivalon the martian surface, the Perseverance landing siteis identified in this high-resolution viewfrom the Mars Reconnaissance Orbiter.The orbiter&amp;rsquo;s camera image also reveals the locationof theMars 2020 missiondescent stage, heat shield, andparachute and back shell that delivered Perseveranceto the surface of Mars. Each annotated inset box spans 200 meters (650 feet) across the floor ofJezero Crater.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mars Perseverance Sol 3</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/marsperseverancesol3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2021 16:03:37 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/marsperseverancesol3/</guid>
      <description>Stitched together on planet Earth,142 separate images make upthis 360 degree panorama from the floor of Jezero Crater on Mars.The high-resolution color images were taken by thePerseverance rover&amp;rsquo;szoomableMastcam-Z duringmission sol 3, also known as February 21, 2021.In the foreground of Mastcam-Z&amp;rsquo;s view is the car-sized rover&amp;rsquo;s deck.Broad light-colored patches in the martian soil just beyond it were scoured bydescent stage rocket engines during therover&amp;rsquo;s dramatic arrivalon February 18.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Venus Flyby</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/avenusflyby/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2021 15:56:18 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/avenusflyby/</guid>
      <description>On a missionto explore the inner heliosphere and solar corona,on July 11, 2020the Wide-field Imager on board NASA&amp;rsquo;sParker Solar Probecapturedthis stunning viewof the nightside of Venus at distance ofabout 12,400 kilometers (7,693 miles).The spacecraft was making the third of seven gravity-assistflybys of the inner planet.The gravity-asssist flybys are designed touse the approachto Venus to help the probe alter its orbit toultimately come within 6 million kilometers (4 million miles)of the solar surface in late 2025.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spiral Galaxy M66 from Hubble</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/spiralgalaxym66fromhubble/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2021 15:47:15 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/spiralgalaxym66fromhubble/</guid>
      <description>It’s always nice to get a new view of an old friend. This stunning Hubble Space Telescope image of nearby spiral galaxy M66 is just that. A spiral galaxy with a small central bar, M66 is a member of the Leo Galaxy Triplet, a group of three galaxies about 30 million light years from us.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moon Rising Between Starships</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/moonrisingbetweenstarships/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2021 14:52:18 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/moonrisingbetweenstarships/</guid>
      <description>What&amp;rsquo;s that on either side of the Moon?Starships.Specifically, they are launch-and-return reusable rockets being developed by SpaceX to lift cargo and eventually humans from the Earth&amp;rsquo;s surface into space. The two rockets pictured are SN9 (Serial Number 9) and SN10 which were captured near their Boca Chica, Texas launchpad last month posing below January&amp;rsquo;s full Wolf Moon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mars Perseverance Sol 0</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/mars_perseverance_sol_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2021 10:18:36 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/mars_perseverance_sol_0/</guid>
      <description>After a 203 day interplanetary voyage, andseven minutes of terror,Perseverance has landed on Mars. Confirmation of the successful landing at Jezero craterwas announced from missioncontrol at NASA’s Jet Propulsion Laboratory in Southern California at12:55 pm PST on February 18.The car-sized Mars rover&amp;rsquo;s Front Left Hazard Avoidance Camera acquired thisinitial low resolution image shortly after touchdown on missionSol 0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Swiss Alps, Martian Sky</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/swiss_alps__martian_sky/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Feb 2021 12:50:12 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/swiss_alps__martian_sky/</guid>
      <description>Taken on February 6,this snowy mountain and skyscape was capturednear Melchsee-Frutt, central Switzerland, planet Earth.The reddish daylight and blue tinted glow around the afternoon Sun arecolors of the Martian sky, though.Of course both worlds have the same Sun.From Mars, the Sun looks only about half as bright and 2/3 the sizecompared to its appearance from Earth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sun Pillar with Upper Tangent Arc</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/sun_pillar_with_upper_tangent_arc/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2021 12:41:52 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/sun_pillar_with_upper_tangent_arc/</guid>
      <description>This was not a typical sun pillar. Just after sunrise two weeks ago in Providence, Rhode Island, USA, a photographer, looking out his window, was suddenly awestruck.The astonishment was caused by a sun pillar that fanned out at the top. Sun pillars, singular columns of light going up from the Sun, are themselves rare to see, and are known to be caused by sunlight reflecting from wobbling, hexagon-shaped ice-disks falling through Earth&amp;rsquo;s atmosphere.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Long Stem Rosette Nebula</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/long_stem_rosette_nebula/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Feb 2021 12:18:02 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/long_stem_rosette_nebula/</guid>
      <description>Would theRosette Nebula by any othername look as sweet?The bland New General Catalogdesignation of NGC 2237 doesn&amp;rsquo;t appear to diminish the appearance of this flowery emission nebula, at the top of the image, atop a long stem of glowing hydrogen gas.Inside the nebula lies anopen clusterof bright young stars designatedNGC 2244.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stereo Eros</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/stereo_eros/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Feb 2021 12:14:57 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/stereo_eros/</guid>
      <description>Get out yourred/blue glassesand float next toasteroid 433 Eros.Orbiting the Sun once every 1.8 years, the near-Earth asteroidis named for the Greek god of love.Still, its shape more closely resembles a lumpy potato than a heart.Eros is a diminutive 40 x 14 x 14 kilometer world of undulating horizons,craters, boulders and valleys.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spiral Galaxy NGC 1350</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/spiral_galaxy_ngc_1350/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2021 12:07:23 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/spiral_galaxy_ngc_1350/</guid>
      <description>This gorgeous island universe lies about 85 million light-yearsdistant in the southernconstellationFornax.Inhabited by young blue star clusters, thetightly woundspiral arms of NGC 1350seem to join in a circle around the galaxy&amp;rsquo;s large,bright nucleus, giving it the appearance of acosmic eye.In fact, NGC 1350 is about 130,000 light-years across.That makes it as large or slightly larger than the Milky Way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cygnus Mosaic 2010 2020</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/cygnus_mosaic_2010_2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2021 11:24:10 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/cygnus_mosaic_2010_2020/</guid>
      <description>In brush strokesof interstellar dust and glowing gas,this beautiful skyscape is painted across the plane of ourMilky Way Galaxynear the northern end of the Great Rift andthe constellation Cygnus the Swan.Composed over a decadewith 400 hours of image data, the broad mosaic spans an impressive28x18 degrees across the sky.Alpha star of Cygnus, bright, hot, supergiantDeneblies at the left.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Firing Lasers to Tame the Sky</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/firing_lasers_to_tame_the_sky/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2021 11:15:24 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/firing_lasers_to_tame_the_sky/</guid>
      <description>Why do stars twinkle?Our atmosphere is to blame as pockets of slightly off-temperature air, in constant motion, distort the light paths from distant astronomical objects.Atmospheric turbulence is a problem for astronomers because it blurs the images of the sources they want to study.The telescope featured in this image, located at ESO’s Paranal Observatory, is equipped with four lasers to combat this turbulence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WR32 and Interstellar Clouds in Carina</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/wr32_and_interstellar_clouds_in_carina/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Feb 2021 10:58:42 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/wr32_and_interstellar_clouds_in_carina/</guid>
      <description>Stars can be like artists.With interstellar gas as a canvas, a massive and tumultuous Wolf-Rayet star has created the picturesque ruffled half-circular filaments called WR32, on the image left.Additionally, the winds and radiation from a small cluster of stars, NGC 3324, have sculpted a 35 light year cavity on the upper right, with its right side appearing as a recognizable face in profile.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Northern Winter Night</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/a_northern_winter_night/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2021 10:41:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/a_northern_winter_night/</guid>
      <description>Snow blanketsthe ground in this serene forest and sky view.Assembled in a 360 degree panoramic projection, the mosaicked frames werecaptured at January&amp;rsquo;s end along a quiet country road nearSiemiony, northeastern Poland,planet Earth.The night was cold and between trees reaching toward the skyshine the stars and nebulae of the northern winterMilky Way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apollo 14 Heads for Home</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/apollo_14_heads_for_home/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2021 10:13:13 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/apollo_14_heads_for_home/</guid>
      <description>Fifty years agothis Sunday (February 7, 1971), the crewof Apollo 14left lunar orbit andheaded for home.They watchedthisEarthrise from their command module Kittyhawk.With Earth&amp;rsquo;s sunlit crescent just peeking over the lunar horizon,the cratered terrain in the foreground is along the lunar farside.Of course, while orbiting the Moon, the crew could watch Earth rise andset, but from the lunar surface the Earth hung stationary in the sky overtheir landing site atFra Mauro Base.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apollo 14: A View from Antares</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/apollo_14__a_view_from_antares/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2021 12:33:46 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/apollo_14__a_view_from_antares/</guid>
      <description>Fifty years agothis Friday, Apollo 14&amp;rsquo;s Lunar Module Antares landed on the Moon.Toward the end of the stay astronaut Ed Mitchell snappeda seriesof photos of the lunar surface while looking out a window,assembledinto this detailed mosaic byApollo LunarSurface Journal editor Eric Jones.The view looks across theFra Mauro highlands to the northwestof the landing site after the Apollo 14 astronauts had completedtheir second and finalwalk on the Moon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Colorful Quadrantid Meteor</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/a_colorful_quadrantid_meteor/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2021 12:07:49 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/a_colorful_quadrantid_meteor/</guid>
      <description>Meteors can be colorful.While the human eye usually cannot discern many colors, cameras often can.Pictured is a Quadrantids meteor captured by camera over Missouri, USA, early this month that was not only impressively bright, but colorful.The radiant grit, likely cast off by asteroid 2003 EH1,blazed a path across Earth&amp;rsquo;s atmosphere. Colors in meteors usually originate from ionized elements released as the meteor disintegrates, with blue-green typically originating from magnesium, calcium radiating violet, and nickel glowing green.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lunar Halo over Snowy Trees</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/lunar_halo_over_snowy_trees/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 12:01:15 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/lunar_halo_over_snowy_trees/</guid>
      <description>Have you ever seen a halo around the Moon? This fairly common sight occurs when high thin clouds containing millions of tiny ice crystals cover much of the sky. Each ice crystal acts like a miniature lens. Because most of the crystals have a similar elongated hexagonal shape, light entering one crystal face and exiting through the opposing face refracts 22 degrees, which corresponds to the radius of the Moon Halo.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Asteroids in the Distance</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/asteroids_in_the_distance/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Jan 2021 11:56:09 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/asteroids_in_the_distance/</guid>
      <description>Rocks from space hit Earth every day. The larger the rock, though, the less often Earth is struck. Many kilograms of space dust pitter to Earth daily.Larger bits appear initially as a bright meteor. Baseball-sized rocks and ice-ballsstreak through our atmosphere daily,most evaporating quickly to nothing. Significant threats do exist for rocks near 100 meters in diameter, whichstrike the Earth roughly every 1000 years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Southern Sky at 38,000 Feet</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/southern_sky_at_38_000_feet/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2021 11:51:38 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/southern_sky_at_38_000_feet/</guid>
      <description>Celestial sights of the southern sky shine above acloudy planet Earth in this gorgeous night sky view.The scene was captured from an airliner&amp;rsquo;s flight deck at 38,000 feeton a steady westbound ride to Lima, Peru.To producethe sharp airborne astrophotograph,the best of a series of shortexposures were selected and digitally stacked.The broad band of thesouthern Milky Way begins at top left withthe darkCoalsack Nebulaand Southern Cross.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>North American Nightscape</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/north_american_nightscape/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2021 11:43:23 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/north_american_nightscape/</guid>
      <description>On January 21, light from the Moon near first quarter illuminated theforeground in this snowy mountain and night scene.Known as The Lions, the striking pair of mountain peaks are north ofVancouver,British Colombia, Canada, North America, planet Earth.Poised above the twin summits, left of Deneb alpha star ofthe constellation Cygnus, are emission regionsNGC 7000 and IC 5070.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Messier 66 Close Up</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/messier_66_close_up/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2021 14:50:40 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/messier_66_close_up/</guid>
      <description>Big, beautifulspiral galaxy Messier 66lies a mere35 million light-years away.The gorgeous island universe isabout 100 thousand light-years across, similar in size to the Milky Way.This reprocessedHubble Space Telescopeclose-up view spans a region about 30,000light-years wide around the galactic core.It shows the galaxy&amp;rsquo;s disk dramatically inclined to our line-of-sight.Surrounding its bright core, the likely home of a supermassive black hole,obscuring dust lanes and young, blue star clusters sweepalong spiral armsdotted with the tell-tale glow of pinksh star forming regions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Vertical Magnetic Field of NGC 5775</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/the_vertical_magnetic_field_of_ngc_5775/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2021 14:30:09 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/the_vertical_magnetic_field_of_ngc_5775/</guid>
      <description>How far do magnetic fields extend up and out of spiral galaxies? For decades astronomers knew only that some spiral galaxies had magnetic fields. However, after NRAO&amp;rsquo;s Very Large Array (VLA) radio telescope (popularized in the movie Contact) was upgraded in 2011, it was unexpectedly discovered that these fields could extend vertically away from the disk by several thousand light-years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Central NGC 1316: After Galaxies Collide</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/central_ngc_1316__after_galaxies_collide/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2021 03:38:03 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/central_ngc_1316__after_galaxies_collide/</guid>
      <description>How did this strange-looking galaxy form? Astronomers turn detectives when trying to figure out the cause of unusual jumbles of stars, gas, and dust like NGC 1316.Inspection indicates that NGC 1316 is an enormous elliptical galaxy that somehow includes dark dust lanes usually found in a spiral galaxy. Detailed images taken by the Hubble Space Telescope shows details, however, that help in reconstructing the history of this gigantic tangle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Southern Cross over Chilean Volcano</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/southern_cross_over_chilean_volcano/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jan 2021 03:09:35 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/southern_cross_over_chilean_volcano/</guid>
      <description>Have you ever seen the Southern Cross?This famous four-star icon is best seen from Earth&amp;rsquo;s Southern Hemisphere.The featured image was taken last month in Chile and captures the Southern Cross just to the left of erupting Villarrica, one of the most active volcanos in our Solar System. Connecting the reddest Southern Cross star Gacrux through the brightest star Acrux points near the most southern location in the sky: the South Celestial Pole (SCP), around which all southern stars appear to spin as the Earth turns.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Massive Nearby Spiral Galaxy NGC 2841</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/massive_nearby_spiral_galaxy_ngc_2841/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2021 02:44:55 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/massive_nearby_spiral_galaxy_ngc_2841/</guid>
      <description>It is one of the more massive galaxies known.A mere 46 million light-years distant, spiral galaxy NGC 2841can be found in the northern constellation ofUrsa Major.This sharp view of the gorgeousisland universeshows off a striking yellow nucleus and galactic disk.Dust lanes, small, pink star-forming regions, and young blue star clustersare embedded in the patchy, tightlywoundspiral arms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recycling Cassiopeia A</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/recycling_cassiopeia_a/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jan 2021 02:22:15 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/recycling_cassiopeia_a/</guid>
      <description>Massive stars in our Milky Way Galaxy live spectacular lives. Collapsing from vast cosmic clouds, their nuclear furnacesignite and create heavy elements in their cores.After a few million years, theenriched material is blastedback into interstellar space where star formation can begin anew.The expanding debris cloud known as Cassiopeia A is an exampleof this final phase of the stellar life cycle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Milky Ring</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/the_milky_ring/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2021 13:57:54 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/the_milky_ring/</guid>
      <description>An expanse of cosmic dust, stars and nebulae alongthe plane of our Milky Way galaxy form a beautiful ring inthis projected all-sky view.The creative panorama covers the entiregalaxy visiblefrom planet Earth,an ambitious 360 degree mosaic that took two years to complete.Northern hemisphere sites in western China and southern hemispheresites in New Zealand were usedto collect the image data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>M78 Wide Field</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/m78_wide_field/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2021 13:36:51 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/m78_wide_field/</guid>
      <description>Interstellardust clouds andglowing nebulaeabound in the fertileconstellation of Orion.One of thebrightest, M78,is centered in this colorful,wide field view,covering an area north ofOrion&amp;rsquo;s belt.At a distance of about 1,500 light-years, thebluish reflection nebula is around 5 light-years across.Its tint is due to dustpreferentiallyreflecting the blue lightof hot, young stars.Reflection nebula NGC 2071 isjustto the left of M78.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Magnetic Field of the Whirlpool Galaxy</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/the_magnetic_field_of_the_whirlpool_galaxy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2021 01:26:57 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/the_magnetic_field_of_the_whirlpool_galaxy/</guid>
      <description>Do magnetic fields always flow along spiral arms? Our face-on view of the Whirlpool Galaxy (M51) allows a spectacularly clear view of the spiral wave pattern in a disk-shaped galaxy. When observed with a radio telescope, the magnetic field appears to trace the arms&amp;rsquo; curvature. However, with NASA’s flying Stratospheric Observatory for Infrared Astronomy (SOFIA) observatory, the magnetic field at the outer edge of M51&amp;rsquo;s disk appears to weave across the arms instead.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Lunar Corona with Jupiter and Saturn</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/a_lunar_corona_with_jupiter_and_saturn/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2021 01:06:18 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/a_lunar_corona_with_jupiter_and_saturn/</guid>
      <description>Why does a cloudy moon sometimes appear colorful?The effect, called a lunar corona, is created by the quantum mechanical diffraction of light around individual, similarly-sized water droplets in an intervening but mostly-transparent cloud.Since light of different colors has different wavelengths, each color diffracts differently.Lunar Coronae are one of the few quantum mechanical color effects that can be easily seen with the unaided eye.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Medulla Nebula Supernova Remnant</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/the_medulla_nebula_supernova_remnant/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2021 13:58:21 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/the_medulla_nebula_supernova_remnant/</guid>
      <description>What powers this unusual nebula?CTB-1 is the expanding gas shell that was left when a massive star toward the constellation of Cassiopeia exploded about 10,000 years ago.The star likely detonated when it ran out of elements, near its core, that could create stabilizing pressure with nuclear fusion.The resulting supernova remnant, nicknamed the Medulla Nebula for its brain-like shape, still glows in visible light by the heat generated by its collision with confining interstellar gas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jets from Unusual Galaxy Centaurus A</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/jets_from_unusual_galaxy_centaurus_a/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2021 01:50:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/jets_from_unusual_galaxy_centaurus_a/</guid>
      <description>The jets emanating fromCentaurus A are over a million light years long.These jets of streamingplasma,expelled by a giant black hole in the center of this spiral galaxy, light up this composite image ofCen A.Exactly how thecentral black holeexpels infalling matter remains unknown.After clearing the galaxy, however,the jets inflate largeradio bubbles that likely glow for millions of years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Mountains of NGC 2174</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/the_mountains_of_ngc_2174/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jan 2021 01:37:20 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/the_mountains_of_ngc_2174/</guid>
      <description>This fantastic skyscapelies near the edgeof NGC 2174 a star formingregion about 6,400 light-years away in the nebula-rich constellationof Orion.It follows mountainous clouds of gas and dust carved bywinds and radiation from the region&amp;rsquo;snewborn stars, now foundscatteredin open star clusters embedded around the center of NGC 2174,off the top of the frame.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Plutonian Landscape</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/a_plutonian_landscape/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2021 13:23:51 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/a_plutonian_landscape/</guid>
      <description>This shadowy landscapeof majestic mountains and icy plainsstretches toward the horizon on a small, distant world.It was captured from a range of about 18,000 kilometers whenNew Horizonslooked back toward Pluto,15 minutes after the spacecraft&amp;rsquo;s closest approach on July 14.The dramatic, low-angle, near-twilightscene follows rugged mountains formally known as Norgay Montesfrom foreground left, and Hillary Montes along the horizon,giving way to smooth Sputnik Planum atright.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aurora Slathers Up the Sky</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/aurora_slathers_up_the_sky/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2021 13:16:06 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/aurora_slathers_up_the_sky/</guid>
      <description>Like salsa verde on your favorite burrito, a greenauroraslathers up the sky in this 2017 June 25 snapshot from theInternational Space Station.About 400 kilometers (250 miles) above Earth,the orbiting station is itselfwithin the upper realmof the auroral displays.Aurorae have thesignaturecolors of excited molecules and atoms at the low densitiesfound at extreme altitudes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arches Across an Arctic Sky</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/arches_across_an_arctic_sky/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jan 2021 13:06:09 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/arches_across_an_arctic_sky/</guid>
      <description>What are these two giant arches across the sky?Perhaps the more familiar one, on the left, is the central band of our Milky Way Galaxy.This grand disk of stars and nebulas here appears to encircle much of the southern sky.Visible below the stellar arch is the rusty-orange planet Mars and the extended Andromeda galaxy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Historic Brazilian Constellation</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/a_historic_brazilian_constellation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2021 12:59:34 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/a_historic_brazilian_constellation/</guid>
      <description>The night sky is filled with stories.Cultures throughout history have projected some of their most enduring legends onto the stars above.Generations of people see these stellar constellations, hear the associated stories, and pass them down.Featured here is the perhaps unfamiliar constellation of the Old Man, long recognized by the Tupi peoples native to regions of South America now known as Brazil.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Star Cluster R136 Breaks Out</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/star_cluster_r136_breaks_out/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2021 12:48:37 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/star_cluster_r136_breaks_out/</guid>
      <description>In the center of nearby star-forming region lies a huge cluster containing some of the largest, hottest, and most massive stars known.These stars, known collectively asstar cluster R136,part of the Tarantula Nebula, were captured in the featured image invisible light in 2009 through the Hubble Space Telescope.Gas and dust clouds in theTarantula Nebula, have been sculpted into elongated shapes by powerfulwinds andultraviolet radiationfrom these hot cluster stars.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Titan: Moon over Saturn</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/titan__moon_over_saturn/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jan 2021 12:43:23 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/titan__moon_over_saturn/</guid>
      <description>Like Earth&amp;rsquo;s moon,Saturn&amp;rsquo;s largest moon Titanis locked in synchronous rotation.This mosaicof images recorded by the Cassini spacecraft in May of 2012shows its anti-Saturn side, the sidealways facing away from theringed gas giant.The only moon in the solar system with a dense atmosphere,Titan is the onlysolar system world besides Earth known tohave standing bodies of liquid on its surface and an earthlikecycle of liquid rain and evaporation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NGC 1365: Majestic Island Universe</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/ngc_1365__majestic_island_universe/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jan 2021 12:38:15 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/ngc_1365__majestic_island_universe/</guid>
      <description>Barred spiral galaxy NGC 1365 is truly a majesticisland universe some 200,000light-years across.Located a mere 60 million light-years away toward the chemicalconstellationFornax,NGC 1365 is adominant member of the well-studiedFornaxCluster of galaxies.This impressivelysharp color imageshows the intense, reddish star forming regions near theends of central bar and along the spiral arms,with details of the obscuring dust lanes cuttingacross the galaxy&amp;rsquo;s bright core.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Total Solar Eclipse 2020</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/total_solar_eclipse_2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2021 06:24:04 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/total_solar_eclipse_2020/</guid>
      <description>Along a narrow pathcrossing southern South America through Chileand Argentina, the final New Moon of 2020moved in front of the Sun on December 14 in the year&amp;rsquo;s onlytotal solar eclipse.Within about 2 days of perigee, the closest point in its ellipticalorbit, the New Moon&amp;rsquo;s surface is faintlylit by earthshinein this dramatic composite view.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Striped Sand Dunes on Mars</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/striped_sand_dunes_on_mars/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2021 06:10:45 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/striped_sand_dunes_on_mars/</guid>
      <description>Why are these sand dunes on Mars striped? No one is sure. The featured image shows striped dunes in Kunowsky Crater on Mars, photographed recently with the Mars Reconnaissance Orbiter’s HiRISE Camera. Many Martian dunes are known to be covered unevenly with carbon dioxide (dry ice) frost, creating patterns of light and dark areas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Small Cloud of Magellan</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/the_small_cloud_of_magellan/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2021 06:26:47 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/the_small_cloud_of_magellan/</guid>
      <description>What is the Small Magellanic Cloud?It has turned out to be a galaxy. People who have wondered about this little fuzzy patch in the southern sky included Portuguese navigatorFerdinand Magellan and his crew, who had plentyof time to study the unfamiliar night sky of the south during thefirst circumnavigation of planet Earth in the early 1500s.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Phoenix Aurora over Iceland</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/a_phoenix_aurora_over_iceland/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2021 06:35:24 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/a_phoenix_aurora_over_iceland/</guid>
      <description>All of the other aurora watchers had gone home.By 3:30 am in Iceland, on a quiet September night, much of that night&amp;rsquo;s auroras had died down.Suddenly, unexpectedly, a new burst of particles streamed down from space, lighting up the Earth&amp;rsquo;s atmosphere once again.This time, surprisingly, pareidoliacally, the night lit up with an amazing shape reminiscent of a giant phoenix.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>21st Century Wet Collodion Moon</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/21st_century_wet_collodion_moon/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 06:25:22 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/21st_century_wet_collodion_moon/</guid>
      <description>In the mid 19th century, one of the first photographic technologies usedto record the lunar surface was thewet-plate collodionprocess, notably employed by British astronomerWarren De la Rue.To capture an image, a thick, transparent mixture wasused to coat a glass plate, sensitized with silvernitrate, exposed at the telescope, and then developedto create a negative image on the plate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Galaxies and the South Celestial Pole</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/galaxies_and_the_south_celestial_pole/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 06:18:44 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/galaxies_and_the_south_celestial_pole/</guid>
      <description>The South Celestial Poleis easy to spot in star trail images of the southern sky.The extension of Earth&amp;rsquo;s axis of rotation to the south, it&amp;rsquo;sat the center of all the southern star trail arcs.In this starry panoramastreching about 60 degrees across deep southern skiesthe South Celestial Pole is somewhere near the middle though,flanked by bright galaxies and southern celestial gems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trail of the Returner</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/trail_of_the_returner/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 06:06:37 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/trail_of_the_returner/</guid>
      <description>Familiar starsof a northern winter&amp;rsquo;s night shine in this nightskyview, taken near Zhangye, Gansu, China and theborder with Inner Mongolia.During the early hours of December 17 Orion is near centerin the single exposure thatcaptures a fireball streakingacross the sky, almost as bright as yellowish Mars shining on the right.Splitting Gemini&amp;rsquo;s twin bright stars Castor and Polluxnear the top of the frame, thefireball&amp;rsquo;s trail and timing are consistent with thesecond skippingatmospheric entry of the Chang&amp;rsquo;e 5 mission&amp;rsquo;s returner capsule.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>M16: Inside the Eagle Nebula</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/m16__inside_the_eagle_nebula/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Dec 2020 06:33:04 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/m16__inside_the_eagle_nebula/</guid>
      <description>From afar, the whole thing looks like an Eagle. A closer look at the Eagle Nebula,however, shows thebrightregion is actually a window into the center of a larger dark shell of dust. Through this window, a brightly-lit workshop appearswhere a whole open cluster of stars is being formed. In this cavity tall pillars and round globules of dark dust and cold molecular gasremain where stars are still forming.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cosmic Latte: The Average Color of the Universe</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/cosmic_latte__the_average_color_of_the_universe/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Dec 2020 06:23:40 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/cosmic_latte__the_average_color_of_the_universe/</guid>
      <description>What color is the universe? More precisely, if theentire sky were smeared out,what color would the final mix be? This whimsical question came up when trying to determinewhat stars are commonplace in nearby galaxies.The answer,depicted above,is a conditionally perceived shade ofbeige.In computer parlance: #FFF8E7. To determine this, astronomers computationally averagedthe light emitted by one of the larger samples ofgalaxies analyzed: the 200,000galaxies of the2dF survey.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fox Fur, Unicorn, and Christmas Tree</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/fox_fur__unicorn__and_christmas_tree/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Dec 2020 06:15:43 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/fox_fur__unicorn__and_christmas_tree/</guid>
      <description>Clouds of glowing hydrogen gas fill this colorful skyscape in the faintbut fanciful constellationMonoceros,the Unicorn.A star forming regioncatalogedas NGC 2264, the complex jumble ofcosmic gas and dust is about 2,700 light-years distant andmixes reddish emission nebulaeexcited by energetic light fromnewborn stars with darkinterstellar dust clouds.Where the otherwise obscuring dust clouds lie closeto the hot, young stars they also reflect starlight, forming bluereflection nebulae.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Northern Winter Night</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/northern_winter_night/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Dec 2020 06:07:15 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/northern_winter_night/</guid>
      <description>Orion always seems to come up sideways onnorthern winter evenings.Those familiar stars of the constellation of the Hunterare caught above the trees in this colorful night skyscape.Not a star at all but still visible to eye,the GreatNebula of Orionshines below the Hunter&amp;rsquo;s belt stars.The camera&amp;rsquo;s exposurereveals the stellar nursery&amp;rsquo;s faint pinkish glow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Portrait of NGC 1055</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/portrait_of_ngc_1055/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Dec 2020 06:23:17 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/portrait_of_ngc_1055/</guid>
      <description>Big, beautiful spiral galaxy NGC 1055 is a dominant member ofa small galaxy groupa mere 60 million light-years away towardthe aquatically intimidating constellation Cetus.Seen edge-on, the island universe spans over 100,000 light-years,a little larger than ourown Milky Way galaxy.The colorful, spiky stars decorating this cosmicportraitof NGC 1055 are in the foreground, well within the Milky Way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jupiter Meets Saturn: A Red Spotted Great Conjunction</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/jupiter_meets_saturn__a_red_spotted_great_conjunction/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2020 06:12:44 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/jupiter_meets_saturn__a_red_spotted_great_conjunction/</guid>
      <description>It was time for their close-up.Last week Jupiter and Saturn passed a tenth of a degree from each other in what is known a Great Conjunction.Although the two planets pass each other on the sky every 20 years, this was the closest pass in nearly four centuries. Taken early in day of the Great Conjunction, the featured multiple-exposure combination captures not only both giant planets in a single frame, but also Jupiter&amp;rsquo;s four largest moons (left to right) Callisto, Ganymede, Io, and Europa &amp;ndash; and Saturn&amp;rsquo;s largest moon Titan.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Solstice: Sunrises Around the Year</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/solstice__sunrises_around_the_year/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Dec 2020 06:12:04 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/solstice__sunrises_around_the_year/</guid>
      <description>Does the Sun always rise in the same direction? No. As the months change, the direction toward the rising Sun changes, too. The featured image shows the direction of sunrise every month during 2019 as seen from near the city of Amman, Jordan. The camera in the image is always facing due east, with north toward the left and south toward the right.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Volcanic Great Conjunction</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/a_volcanic_great_conjunction/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Dec 2020 06:29:07 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/a_volcanic_great_conjunction/</guid>
      <description>Where can I see the Great Conjunction? Near where the Sun just set.Directionally, this close passing of Jupiter and Saturn will be toward the southwest. Since the planetary pair, the Sun, and the Earth are nearly in a geometric straight line, the planets will be seen to set just where the Sun had set &amp;ndash; from every location on Earth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conjunction after Sunset</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/conjunction_after_sunset/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Dec 2020 06:19:52 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/conjunction_after_sunset/</guid>
      <description>How close will Jupiter and Saturn be at theirGreat Conjunction?Consider this beautiful triple conjunction of Moon, Jupiter andSaturn captured through clouds in the wintry twilight.The telephoto viewlooks toward the western horizonand the Alborz Mountains in Iran after sunset on December 17.The celestial gatheringmakes it easy to see Jupiter and fainter Saturn are separated on that date byroughly the diameter of the waxing crescent Moon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Diamond in the Sky</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/diamond_in_the_sky/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Dec 2020 06:06:09 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/diamond_in_the_sky/</guid>
      <description>When the shadow of the Moon raced across planet Earth&amp;rsquo;ssouthern hemisphere on December 14,sky watchers along the shadow&amp;rsquo;s darkcentral pathwere treated to the only total solar eclipse of 2020.During theNew Moon&amp;rsquo;s shadow playthis glistening diamond ring was seenfor a moment, even in cloudy skies.Known as thediamond ring effect,the transient spectacle actually happens twice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gemini s Meteors</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/gemini_s_meteors/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2020 06:21:25 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/gemini_s_meteors/</guid>
      <description>Taken over the course of an hour shortly after local midnight on December 13,35 exposures were used to create this postcard from Earth.The composited night scene spans dark skies above the snowy ItalianDolomites during our fair planet&amp;rsquo;sannual Geminid meteor shower.Sirius, alpha star of Canis Major and the brightest star in the night,is grazed by a meteor streak on the right.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Great Conjunction: Saturn and Jupiter Converge</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/great_conjunction__saturn_and_jupiter_converge/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2020 06:27:42 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/great_conjunction__saturn_and_jupiter_converge/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s happening.Saturn and Jupiter are moving closer and will soon appear in almost exactly the same direction. Coincidentally, on the night of the December solstice &amp;ndash; the longest night of the year in the north and the longest day in the south &amp;ndash; the long-awaited Great Conjunction will occur.Then, about six days from now, Saturn and Jupiter will be right next to each other &amp;ndash; as they are every 20 years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Geminid Meteors over Xinglong Observatory</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/geminid_meteors_over_xinglong_observatory/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Dec 2020 06:35:30 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/geminid_meteors_over_xinglong_observatory/</guid>
      <description>Where do Geminid meteors come from? In terms of location on the sky, as the featured image composite beautifully demonstrates, the sand-sized bits of rock that create the streaks of the Geminids meteor shower appear to flow out from the constellation of Gemini.In terms of parent body,Solar System trajectories point to the asteroid 3200 Phaethon &amp;ndash; but this results in a bit of a mystery since that unusual object appears mostly dormant.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Saturn and Jupiter in Summer 2020</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/saturn_and_jupiter_in_summer_2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2020 06:26:32 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/saturn_and_jupiter_in_summer_2020/</guid>
      <description>During this northern summer Saturn and Jupiter were both near opposition,opposite the Sun in planet Earth&amp;rsquo;s sky.Their paired retrogrademotion, seen about every 20 years, is followedfrom 19 June through 28 Augustin this panoramic composite as they wandertogether between the stars in western Capricornus and easternSagittarius.But this December&amp;rsquo;s skies find them drawing even closer together.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Messier Craters in Stereo</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/messier_craters_in_stereo/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Dec 2020 06:13:20 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/messier_craters_in_stereo/</guid>
      <description>Many bright nebulae and star clusters in planet Earth&amp;rsquo;s skyare associated with the name ofastronomer Charles Messierfrom his famous 18th century catalog.His name is also given to these two large and remarkable craterson the Moon.Standouts in the dark,smooth lunar Sea of Fertility or MareFecunditatis, Messier (left) and Messier A have dimensions of 15 by 8and 16 by 11 kilometers respectively.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simeis 147: Supernova Remnant</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/simeis_147__supernova_remnant/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2020 06:31:03 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/simeis_147__supernova_remnant/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s easy to get lost following the intricate looping filaments inthis detailed image ofsupernova remnant Simeis 147.Also cataloged as Sharpless 2-240 it goes by the popular nickname,the Spaghetti Nebula.Seen towardthe boundary of the constellations Taurus and Auriga,it covers nearly 3 degrees or 6 full moons on the sky.That&amp;rsquo;s about 150 light-years atthe stellar debris cloud&amp;rsquo;s estimated distance of 3,000 light-years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Great Conjunction over Sicilian Lighthouse</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/great_conjunction_over_sicilian_lighthouse/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2020 06:13:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/great_conjunction_over_sicilian_lighthouse/</guid>
      <description>Don’t miss the coming great conjunction.In just under two weeks, the two largest planets in our Solar System will angularly pass so close together in Earth&amp;rsquo;s sky that the Moon would easily be able to cover them both simultaneously. This pending planetary passage &amp;ndash; on December 21 &amp;ndash; will be the closest since 1623.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mammatus Clouds over Mount Rushmore</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/mammatus_clouds_over_mount_rushmore/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2020 06:32:07 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/mammatus_clouds_over_mount_rushmore/</guid>
      <description>What&amp;rsquo;s that below those strange clouds?Presidents.If you look closely, you may recognize the heads of four former US Presidents carved into famous Mount Rushmore in South Dakota, USA. More obvious in the featured image are the unusual mammatus clouds that passed briefly overhead.Both were captured together by a surprised tourist with a quick camera in early September.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>M16: Pillars of Star Creation</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/m16__pillars_of_star_creation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Dec 2020 06:22:13 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/m16__pillars_of_star_creation/</guid>
      <description>These dark pillars may look destructive, but they are creating stars. This pillar-capturing image of the inside of the Eagle Nebula, taken with the Hubble Space Telescope in 1995, shows evaporating gaseous globules (EGGs) emerging from pillars of molecular hydrogen gas and dust. The giant pillars are light years in length and are so dense that interior gas contracts gravitationally to form stars.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mons Rumker in the Ocean of Storms</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/mons_rumker_in_the_ocean_of_storms/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Dec 2020 06:12:37 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/mons_rumker_in_the_ocean_of_storms/</guid>
      <description>Mons Rumker,a 70 kilometer widecomplex of volcanic domes,rises some 1100 meters abovethe vast, smooth lunar mare known as Oceanus Procellarum,the Ocean of Storms.Daylight came to the area late last month.The lunar terminator, theshadow line between night and day, runs diagonally across theleft side in this telescopic close-up of a waxing gibbous Moonfrom November 27.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Curly Spiral Galaxy M63</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/curly_spiral_galaxy_m63/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2020 06:27:16 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/curly_spiral_galaxy_m63/</guid>
      <description>A bright spiral galaxy of the northern sky,Messier 63is nearby,about 30 million light-years distant toward the loyal constellationCanes Venatici.Also cataloged as NGC 5055, the majesticisland universeis nearly 100,000 light-years across, about the sizeof our own Milky Way.Its bright coreand majesticspiral arms lend the galaxyits popular name, The Sunflower Galaxy,while this exceptionally deep exposure also followsfaint, arcing star streams far into the galaxy&amp;rsquo;shalo.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Antennae Galaxies in Collision</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/the_antennae_galaxies_in_collision/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2020 06:11:40 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/the_antennae_galaxies_in_collision/</guid>
      <description>Sixty million light-years away toward the southerly constellation Corvus,these two large galaxies are colliding.The cosmic train wreck captured in stunning detail in thisHubble Space Telescope snapshottakes hundreds of millions of years to play out.Cataloged as NGC 4038 and NGC 4039, the galaxies&amp;rsquo; individual stars don&amp;rsquo;toften collide though.Their large clouds of molecular gas and dust do,triggering furious episodes of star formation near the center ofthe wreckage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eye of Moon</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/eye_of_moon/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2020 06:28:55 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/eye_of_moon/</guid>
      <description>Who&amp;rsquo;s watching who? The featured image of the Moon through a gap in a wall of rock may appear like a giant eye looking back at you. Although, in late October, it took only a single exposure to capture this visual double, it also took a lot of planning. The photographic goal was achieved by precise timing &amp;ndash; needed for a nearly full moon to appear through the eye-shaped arch, by precise locating &amp;ndash; needed for the angular size of the Moon to fit iconically inside the rock arch, and by good luck &amp;ndash; needed for a clear sky and for the entire scheme to work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NGC 346: Star Forming Cluster in the SMC</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/ngc_346__star_forming_cluster_in_the_smc/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2020 06:11:34 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/ngc_346__star_forming_cluster_in_the_smc/</guid>
      <description>Are stars still forming in the Milky Way&amp;rsquo;s satellite galaxies? Found among the Small Magellanic Cloud&amp;rsquo;s (SMC&amp;rsquo;s) clusters and nebulas,NGC 346 isa star forming region about 200 light-years across,pictured here in the center of a Hubble Space Telescope image.A satellite galaxy of the Milky Way, the Small Magellanic Cloud(SMC)is a wonder of the southern sky, a mere210,000 light-years distant in the constellation of the Toucan (Tucana).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cygnus Without Stars</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/cygnus_without_stars/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 06:25:36 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/cygnus_without_stars/</guid>
      <description>The sky is filled with faintly glowing gas, though it can take asensitive camera and telescope to see it.For example, this twelve-degree-wide view of thenorthern part of the constellationCygnusreveals a complex array of cosmic clouds of gasalong the plane of our Milky Way galaxy.The featured mosaic of telescopic images was recorded through two filters: an H-alpha filter that transmits only visible red light fromglowing hydrogen atoms,and a blue filter that transmits primarily light emitted by the slightamount of energized oxygen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Verona Rupes: Tallest Known Cliff in the Solar System</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/verona_rupes__tallest_known_cliff_in_the_solar_system/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Nov 2020 06:11:56 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/verona_rupes__tallest_known_cliff_in_the_solar_system/</guid>
      <description>Could you survive a jump off the tallest cliff in the Solar System?Quite possibly. Verona Rupes onUranus&amp;rsquo; moonMirandais estimated to be 20 kilometers deep &amp;ndash; ten times the depth of theEarth&amp;rsquo;s Grand Canyon. GivenMiranda&amp;rsquo;s low gravity, it would take about 12 minutes for a thrill-seeking adventurer to fall from the top, reaching the bottom at the speed of aracecar &amp;ndash; about 200 kilometers per hour.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NGC 6822: Barnard s Galaxy</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/ngc_6822__barnard_s_galaxy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2020 11:34:51 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/ngc_6822__barnard_s_galaxy/</guid>
      <description>Grand spiral galaxiesoften seem to get all the glory, flaunting theiryoung, bright, blue star clusters in beautiful, symmetric spiral arms.But small galaxies form stars too, like nearby NGC 6822, also known asBarnard&amp;rsquo;sGalaxy.Beyond the rich starfields in the constellation Sagittarius,NGC 6822 is a mere 1.5 million light-years away, a member of ourLocal Groupof galaxies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chang e 5 Mission Launch</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/chang_e_5_mission_launch/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Nov 2020 06:30:56 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/chang_e_5_mission_launch/</guid>
      <description>This Long March-5 rocket blasted off from theWenchang launch sitein southernmost Hainan province on TuesdayNovember 24, at 4:30 am Beijing Time,carrying China&amp;rsquo;sChang&amp;rsquo;e-5 mission to the Moon.The lunar landing mission is named for the ancient Chinese goddess of the moon.Its goal is to collectabout 2 kilograms (4.4 pounds) oflunar material from the surface and return itto planet Earth, the first robotic sample return mission to theMoon since the Soviet Union&amp;rsquo;sLuna 24 missionin 1976.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Great Turkey Nebula</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/the_great_turkey_nebula/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Nov 2020 06:17:53 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/the_great_turkey_nebula/</guid>
      <description>Surprisingly reminiscent of The Great Nebula in Orion,The Great Turkey Nebula spans this creative field of view. Of courseif it were the Orion Nebula it would be our closestlarge stellar nursery, found at the edge of a large molecular clouda mere 1,500 light-years away.Also known as M42,the Orion Nebula is visible to the eye as the middle&amp;quot;star&amp;rdquo; in the sword of Orion the Hunter, a constellationnow rising in planet Earth&amp;rsquo;sevening skies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Andromeda over Patagonia</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/andromeda_over_patagonia/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Nov 2020 06:06:50 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/andromeda_over_patagonia/</guid>
      <description>How far can you see? The Andromeda Galaxy at 2.5 million light years away is the most distant object easily seen with your unaided eye. Most other apparent denizens of the night sky &amp;ndash; stars, clusters, and nebulae &amp;ndash; typically range from a few hundred to a few thousand light-years away and lie well within our own Milky Way Galaxy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Helix Nebula from CFHT</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/the_helix_nebula_from_cfht/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2020 06:24:49 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/the_helix_nebula_from_cfht/</guid>
      <description>Will our Sun look like this one day? The Helix Nebula is one of brightest and closest examples of aplanetary nebula, a gascloud created at the end of the life of a Sun-like star.The outer gasses of the starexpelled into space appear from ourvantage point as if we are looking down a helix.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Jupiter Vista from Juno</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/a_jupiter_vista_from_juno/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2020 06:35:42 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/a_jupiter_vista_from_juno/</guid>
      <description>Why do colorful cloud bands encircle Jupiter?Jupiter&amp;rsquo;s top atmospheric layer is divided into light zones and dark belts that go all the way around the giant planet.It is high horizontal winds &amp;ndash; in excess of 300 kilometers per hour &amp;ndash; that cause the zones to spread out planet-wide.What causes these strong winds remains a topic of research.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dark Molecular Cloud Barnard 68</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/dark_molecular_cloud_barnard_68/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Nov 2020 06:09:02 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/dark_molecular_cloud_barnard_68/</guid>
      <description>Where did all the stars go? What used to be considered a hole in the skyis now known to astronomers as a dark molecular cloud. Here, a high concentration ofdust andmolecular gasabsorb practically all the visible lightemitted from background stars. The eerily dark surroundings help make the interiors ofmolecular clouds some of the coldestand most isolated places in the universe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mars and Meteor over Jade Dragon Snow Mountain</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/mars_and_meteor_over_jade_dragon_snow_mountain/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Nov 2020 06:29:42 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/mars_and_meteor_over_jade_dragon_snow_mountain/</guid>
      <description>A brilliant yellowish celestial beacon, Mars stilldazzles in the night.Peering between clouds the wandering planet wasbriefly joined by the flash of a meteor in this moonlessdark sky on November 18.The single exposure was taken as the Earth swept up dust fromperiodic comet Tempel-Tuttle during the annualLeonid Meteor Shower.The view of a rugged western horizon looks alongthe Yulong mountain range in Yunnan province, southwestern China.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Global Map: Mars at Opposition</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/global_map__mars_at_opposition/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2020 06:18:01 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/global_map__mars_at_opposition/</guid>
      <description>This may be the best global Mars map made with a telescope based onplanet Earth.The image data were captured by a team of observers over six long nightsat the Pic du Midi mountaintop observatorybetween October 8 and November 1,when thefourth rock from the Sunhad not wandered far from its 2020opposition and its biggest and brightest appearance in Earth&amp;rsquo;s night sky.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crew 1 Mission Launch Streak</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/crew_1_mission_launch_streak/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Nov 2020 06:30:56 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/crew_1_mission_launch_streak/</guid>
      <description>Leaving planet Earthfor a moment, a SpaceX Falcon 9 rocket arcedinto the early evening sky last Sunday at 7:27 pm EST.This 3 minute 20 second exposure traces the launch streakover Kennedy Space Center&amp;rsquo;s Launch Complex 39A.The rocket carried four astronauts en route tothe International Space Station on the first flight of a NASA-certifiedcommercial human spacecraft system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Double Star Cluster in Perseus</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/a_double_star_cluster_in_perseus/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2020 06:28:37 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/a_double_star_cluster_in_perseus/</guid>
      <description>Most star clusters are singularly impressive. Open clusters NGC 869 and NGC 884, however, could be considered doubly impressive. Also known as &amp;ldquo;h and chi Persei&amp;rdquo;, this unusual double cluster, shown above, is bright enough to be seen from a dark location without even binoculars. Although their discovery surely predates recorded history, the Greek astronomer Hipparchus notably cataloged the double cluster.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Glowing STEVE and the Milky Way</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/a_glowing_steve_and_the_milky_way/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2020 06:11:38 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/a_glowing_steve_and_the_milky_way/</guid>
      <description>What&amp;rsquo;s creating these long glowing streaks in the sky?No one is sure. Known as Strong Thermal Emission Velocity Enhancements (STEVEs), these luminous light-purple sky ribbons may resemble regular auroras, but recent research reveals significant differences.A STEVE&amp;rsquo;s great length and unusual colors, when measured precisely, indicate that it may be related to a subauroral ion drift (SAID), a supersonic river of hot atmospheric ions thought previously to be invisible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Light and Glory over Crete</title>
      <link>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/light_and_glory_over_crete/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Nov 2020 14:27:22 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drpaneas.net/starlordgr/public/en/post/light_and_glory_over_crete/</guid>
      <description>The month was July, the place was the Greek island of Crete, and the sky was spectacular.Of course there were the usual stars like Polaris, Vega, and Antares &amp;ndash; and that common asterism everyone knows: the Big Dipper.But this sky was just getting started. The band of the Milky Way Galaxy stunned as it arched across the night like a bridge made of stars and dust but dotted with red nebula like candy.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>